<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5D2EA37DFA684636ACA4E75248171095" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8622 IH: Medicare Physician Data-driven Performance Payment System Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8622</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to transform the Merit-based Incentive Payment System into the Data-driven Performance Payment System under the Medicare physician fee schedule, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9C4E180AA74F43A8B940B45E6D44A06C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5AAEC69AC5DC431C84B7D1368C615C43" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Physician Data-driven Performance Payment System Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC0BFC643F65C4643A6A669A87A6C5C01"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transforming the Merit-based Incentive Payment System into the Data-driven Performance Payment System</header> <subsection id="H7A0E7DAF2DA14F39B917B989C5C486A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation of the Data-driven Performance Payment System</header> <paragraph id="HDE8DDA7170984A9190D2CAE5D7D70DDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective January 1, 2027, there is established the Data-driven Performance Payment System, which shall consist of the payment system under section 1848(q) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)</external-xref>), including as amended by this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF5D8AACF6C84CC492EA099C1C4269E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (3), any reference to the payment system under section 1848(q) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)</external-xref>), including the terms <quote>Merit-based Incentive Payment System</quote> and <quote>MIPS</quote>, shall be deemed a reference to the <quote>Data-driven Performance Payment System</quote> and <quote>DPPS</quote>, respectively.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB00AB01439264A889109BD72B00A1886"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to provide for an orderly transition and avoid provider confusion, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide for an appropriate transition in the use of the terms <quote>Merit-based Incentive Payment System</quote> (and <quote>MIPS</quote>) and <quote>Data-driven Performance Payment System</quote> (and <quote>DPPS</quote>) in reference to the payment system under section 1848(q) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)</external-xref>). Before the completion of such transition, any reference to the <quote>Data-driven Performance Payment System</quote> (or <quote>DPPS</quote>) shall be deemed to include a reference to the <quote>Merit-based Incentive Payment System</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D2DBAC650C54E68BA71E82068A469C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reforming application of adjustment factors</header> 
<paragraph id="HB7919C0CB9D740749CB7BD628F61E2E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1848(q)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF96AFA9C4AA4C7080076530D64F546B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H73C8CEEC45224818ABCA25FE3764AE54"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>for years before 2028,</quote> after <quote>Taking into account paragraph (1)(G),</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HD6D44341367E4D3FB64B51EB2D251026"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> 
<subclause id="H426D1A6C8B9845B99E833963893B0079"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>clause (iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subclause (III)</quote>;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0E675096C54342639636C6F84CA933F9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>clause (iv)</quote> and inserting <quote>subclause (IV)</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8F4BB8DFEC684492803C8EDDF2D1D79F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE85BA9E2D6514122B1D15F3AC696E273"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>clause (ii)(I)</quote> and inserting <quote>subclause (II)(aa)</quote>; </text></clause> 
<clause id="HD949F5F1EE1D4598882A8D42541F627C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iv)—</text> <subclause id="HF94124B1510E4287ADB1FCA743250600"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subclause (II)</quote> and inserting <quote>item (bb)</quote>;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H717C8D6BC7824DC1B635484AE2341EA2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>clause (ii)(II)</quote> and inserting <quote>subclause (II)(bb)</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H78AE73DC663642D7B15535B530909AFD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HD521274BC0E84B7684F9B77A217E480E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) through (iv) as subclauses (I) through (IV) and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></clause> <clause id="HCA13297259184C9989A5521896DAF299"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Taking into account</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC6BBA9612B044DD9A0D95B0C832515C3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H0252B4831A704B1380F987930002FACA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Adjustment factors for years before 2028</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taking into account</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H01C6D72C8E1B433E92CFD16225C928D8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0C00DCF4174349358F8102F3C5C3796F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HB32A9C14BA984BEF878A0B9D4CD622A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjustment factors for 2028 and subsequent years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For 2028 and each subsequent year, the DPPS adjustment factor specified under this subparagraph for a DPPS eligible professional for such year shall be equal to—</text> <subclause id="H6A3696C3F4844DB9B4C1700D1BFAD109"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (F)(v), in the case of a DPPS eligible professional with a composite performance score for such year above the performance threshold established under subparagraph (D) for such year, 1.25;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H00066ACE046D4028A7D9B37A0AB5F039"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a DPPS eligible professional with a composite performance score for such year equal to such performance threshold, 1;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0FBE64A8AE544D6099E6FE750A9F435A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a DPPS eligible professional not described in <internal-xref idref="H871D4B3774564E0388CCF6B749D63699" legis-path="(ii)(IV)">subclause (IV)</internal-xref> with a composite performance score for such year below such performance threshold, 0.75; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H871D4B3774564E0388CCF6B749D63699"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a DPPS eligible professional who is treated under paragraph (5)(B)(i) as achieving the lowest potential score applicable to each applicable measure or activity that is required to be reported by the professional for such year, 0.5.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5C854C70C9D4B17AC3465D6D12F7ACA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(iv), by striking <quote>and subsequent years</quote> and inserting <quote>and each subsequent year through 2027</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6146C88C502C4FFBBFE1258CFBD0984C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(i), by striking <quote>that are positive, negative, and zero</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92531799B99143E7B8A853420C4D4F0B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)—</text> 
<clause id="HF7CA98DF882E45BDA13C50F14CDC511F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and ending with 2027</quote> after <quote>beginning with 2019</quote>; </text></clause> <clause id="HB919FFB87C8549D0895EDF71C96B9D01"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> 
<subclause id="H0DEC600AF94E47EBA2B4887A381D12B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A)(i)</quote>; and </text></subclause> <subclause id="H429E5E0E00C54ACEA0221AF0D0B624E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H106C46FA6F504DB0B1A40963772D29A0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subclauses (I) and (II), respectively;</text></clause> <clause id="H30E22D75B4E74019A59C931935F8C330"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In the case of</quote> and inserting the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3854BBCBC9D34367AB8A9D20C05CE94F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H8997F0EB0A14433D81F527560A564BE5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application of adjustment factors for years before 2028</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="HCDC1D9E3FFEA419CB6B0B5FD8240F073"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H55E9DCB4E30E465482F81BA5BAB3B5FD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HB08C5744F2F6435B8E4B2856A2D9D334"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Application of adjustment factors for 2028 and subsequent years</header> 
<subclause id="H10C4784F1700463FA18E8957389046A9" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of covered professional services (as defined in subsection (k)(3)(A)) furnished by a DPPS eligible professional during a year (beginning with 2028), subject to subclauses (II) and (III), for purposes of determining the amount paid under this part with respect to such covered professional services and DPPS eligible professional for such year, the update to the nonqualifying APM conversion factor established under subsection (d) applicable to such services and such professional for such year shall be multiplied by the adjustment factor specified under subparagraph (A)(ii) with respect to such professional and such year.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4E5A95A5464B4EEA9139206021BB3256"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Nonapplication to certain updates</header><text><internal-xref idref="H10C4784F1700463FA18E8957389046A9" legis-path="(ii)(I)">Subclause (I)</internal-xref> shall not apply with respect to covered professional services furnished during a year in the case that the update to the conversion factor described in such subclause for such year is less than 0 percent.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAEFE242CCF494C4682815BD3AB069020"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Nonapplication of certain adjustment factors for lack of timely feedback reports</header> 
<item id="H9C02EBBBF94C40179086FD31D2C60988"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><internal-xref idref="H10C4784F1700463FA18E8957389046A9" legis-path="(ii)(I)">Subclause (I)</internal-xref> shall not apply with respect to covered professional services furnished by a DPPS eligible professional during a year if the DPPS eligible professional does not receive timely feedback in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H5D56AA2AF54C4D95808BCB6A77778D53" legis-path="(ii)(III)(cc)">item (bb)</internal-xref> with respect to each quarter of the performance period for such year and would, without application of this item, otherwise be subject to the DPPS adjustment factor described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(III) for such year.</text></item> <item id="H5D56AA2AF54C4D95808BCB6A77778D53" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Timely feedback described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H9C4E180AA74F43A8B940B45E6D44A06C" legis-path="(ii)(III)(aa)">item (aa)</internal-xref>, a DPPS eligible professional receives timely feedback in accordance with this item with respect to a quarter of a performance period if, not later than the date that is 60 days after the last day of such quarter, such professional receives the confidential feedback required under paragraph (12) on the performance of such professional during such quarter with respect to administrative claims-based measures included in the performance categories described in subparagraph (A)(i)(II) of such paragraph, including—</text> 
<subitem id="HA728E271C8BE4D15A354E701A75137EA" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the patients and episodes attributed with respect to such measures for purposes of assessing the performance of such professional during such quarter;</text></subitem> <subitem id="H2C1EC98A007B497CB04EE483A612930E" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>an identification of the items and services furnished by such professional or another individual that will contribute to the assessment of the performance of such professional during such quarter with respect to such measures; and</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="HEF28D9B8FB18470A96433C1FB0144277" commented="no"><enum>(CC)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of whether each item or service identified under <internal-xref idref="H2C1EC98A007B497CB04EE483A612930E" legis-path="(ii)(III)(bb)(BB)">subitem (BB)</internal-xref> for the quarter was furnished by such professional or another individual (and, in the case that the performance of such professional for such quarter with respect to such measures is assessed based on participation in a group practice or other group, whether each such item or service was furnished by such professional, another individual in such group, or another individual outside of such group). </text></subitem></item> </subclause> <subclause id="H02E2B31639B04571A0169536335E4D0F"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Hold harmless</header><text>In computing the amount of any coinsurance under section 1833(a)(1) and the expenses incurred for applying the deductible under section 1833(b) with respect to covered professional services furnished by a DPPS eligible professional for a year, such coinsurance and incurred expenses shall be computed as if the update to the conversion factor applicable to such services and professional for such year were not subject to the adjustment factor under subclause (I).</text></subclause> </clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69C0ABBBFE7D479D9AC1218AE8C3D7E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1848(d)(20) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(d)(20)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, subject to subsection (q)(6)(E)(ii),</quote> before <quote>the update to the nonqualifying APM conversion factor</quote>. </text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H724489382418498E9B8F3081AC9B4ED8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reforming performance thresholds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1848(q)(6)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)(6)(D)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE708E1ECEB654ABA8725FB28114F4872" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>clauses (iii) and (iv)</quote> and inserting <quote>clauses (iii) through (vi)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H179E71535CDE4F57BF0FDADB13706C82" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clauses:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC98960686F174EDB8E66C8FDA0870B9C"> 
<clause id="HBFD3C705F8DF4814B122B5A8FA755DB7" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Temporary extension of special rules</header> 
<subclause id="H1252A361BED54895A5AFF7C63CE55F64"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to each of 2028 through 2033 (or such later year as determined by the Secretary pursuant to <internal-xref idref="HF5AEAB05405740BCB8FFA65F40E2636E" legis-path="(v)(II)">subclause (II)</internal-xref>), the Secretary shall establish a performance threshold for purposes of determining DPPS adjustment factors under subparagraph (A) for such year in accordance with the requirements described in clause (iii), except that such performance threshold may not be greater than 75 points.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF5AEAB05405740BCB8FFA65F40E2636E"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Flexibility to extend special rule</header><text>In the case that extraordinary circumstances, including a natural disaster, a public health emergency, or cybersecurity incident, affect reporting, data collection, or the assessment of performance under this subsection for 2034, the Secretary may extend the application of <internal-xref idref="H1252A361BED54895A5AFF7C63CE55F64" legis-path="(v)(I)">subclause (I)</internal-xref> until the first year for which such extraordinary circumstances do not affect reporting, data collection, or assessment of performance under this subsection (as determined by the Secretary).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H77B8CE4A1B264976965FA1F403C53E5E"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Optional transition period</header><text>With respect to the year immediately following the last year with respect to which <internal-xref idref="HBFD3C705F8DF4814B122B5A8FA755DB7" legis-path="(v)">subclause (I)</internal-xref> applies (after application of <internal-xref idref="HF5AEAB05405740BCB8FFA65F40E2636E" legis-path="(v)(II)">subclause (II)</internal-xref>, if applicable), the Secretary may, pursuant to notice and comment rulemaking, establish a performance threshold for purposes of determining DPPS adjustment factors under subparagraph (A) for such year and such subsequent consecutive years as specified by the Secretary in a manner that provides for a gradual and incremental transition from the performance threshold established under <internal-xref idref="HBFD3C705F8DF4814B122B5A8FA755DB7" legis-path="(v)">subclause (I)</internal-xref> to the performance threshold established under <internal-xref idref="H9C4E180AA74F43A8B940B45E6D44A06C" legis-path="(vii)">clause (vi)</internal-xref>.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC4530F4293544B13BFCC692478606429" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Replacement performance threshold</header> <subclause id="H966AC8FA7FB8418C830E8211F05FCEB0"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the year immediately following the last year with respect to which <internal-xref idref="HBFD3C705F8DF4814B122B5A8FA755DB7" legis-path="(v)">clause (v)</internal-xref> applies and each subsequent year, the performance threshold established under this subparagraph for purposes of determining DPPS adjustment factors under subparagraph (A) shall be computed in accordance with the replacement performance threshold methodology established by the Secretary under in <internal-xref idref="HBAC6A2EDDFD440FF9830545FF95E4C6A" legis-path="(vi)(II)">subclause (II)</internal-xref>.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBAC6A2EDDFD440FF9830545FF95E4C6A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Replacement performance threshold methodology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H966AC8FA7FB8418C830E8211F05FCEB0" legis-path="(vi)(I)">subclause (I)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall, pursuant to notice and comment rulemaking and based on the recommendations submitted under subclause (III), establish a methodology (referred to in this clause as the <quote>replacement performance threshold methodology</quote>) to be used instead of the mean or median described in clause (i) for computing the performance threshold applied under this subparagraph.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H63F8F0DDE4884F92905CFB881C47FFAB"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Recommendations for replacement performance threshold methodology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2029, the Comptroller General of the United States shall, in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H9F55F97A6DC34B57AFC197C52031AD95" legis-path="(vi)(IV)">subclause (IV)</internal-xref>, submit to Congress and the Secretary a report including detailed recommendations on a methodology to be used instead of the mean or median described in clause (i) for computing the performance threshold described in <internal-xref idref="H966AC8FA7FB8418C830E8211F05FCEB0" legis-path="(vi)(I)">subclause (I)</internal-xref> and that is based on data that are accurate and reliable.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9F55F97A6DC34B57AFC197C52031AD95"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Recommendation requirements</header><text>In making the recommendations required under <internal-xref idref="H63F8F0DDE4884F92905CFB881C47FFAB" legis-path="(vi)(III)">subclause (III)</internal-xref>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text> <item id="HF52161C431254E4B9120B41C6B50093D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>seek to prevent unintended consequences that may result from weighing quality and cost performance categories;</text></item> 
<item id="H6D2CB8E84260454E83D350E9931ED0EA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>consider the impact of such recommendations on different types of DPPS eligible professionals, including such professionals in a small group practice and such professionals that serve rural or underserved communities; and</text></item> <item id="HF7BFA7669DBB4951B324040F6AF873E2"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>consult with stakeholders, including organizations representing physicians.</text></item></subclause></clause> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H02D6533A968F49C18284A08E04BC7DA2" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintaining budget neutrality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1848(q)(6)(F) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)(6)(F)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H01DE46D996384EDBBB162E20E08752BA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3483149FD8FE445081CAF2036B61218D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the clause heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">for years before 2028</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">factor</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E91715EB716491A919529DBFE847C32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (I)—</text> 
<clause id="HECE2321086294BE1B7275734ED5EA04A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>With respect</quote> and inserting <quote>For years before 2028, with respect</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA1D6BB54130D40C1A42782CB4D77BE76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (A)(ii)(I)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A)(i)(II)(aa)</quote>; </text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FE895DD83B14E9294D46F519AAD451C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0B76C67018A447F9845962B90D7B1E75" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the clause heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">for years before 2028</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">requirement</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59D4BE91A29D407989175A3A6CBE8665"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>Subject to</quote> and inserting <quote>For years before 2028, subject to</quote>;</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E0E895490B14C1F88F39254FF9A085A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (iii)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7971AEF974514BF3BCCFBD4C8D107AAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by inserting <quote>before 2028</quote> before <quote>that are below</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8891125B8C9430C8C12EC0B52B80921"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by inserting <quote>before 2028</quote> after <quote>with respect to a year</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF30C1EAE41934A88AF09451500896BFD" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block id="H824198369D2F42EA98403F473EA34B63" style="OLC"> <clause id="HAE7A960660CB4C499DD5E672BD6EACB2"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Budget neutrality for 2028 and subsequent years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For 2028 and each subsequent year, the Secretary shall decrease DPPS adjustment factors under subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) for DPPS eligible professionals whose composite performance score for such year is above the performance threshold established under subparagraph (D) for such year in order to ensure that the estimated increase in the aggregate allowed charges resulting from the application of such adjustment factors (after application of this clause) to such professionals for such year is not more than the estimated decrease in such charges resulting from the application for such year of DPPS adjustment factors under subclauses (III) and (IV) of subparagraph (A)(ii) to DPPS eligible professionals whose composite performance score for such year is below such performance threshold.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD4CA94EDD0B24574B25C5E9BD4414617" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Investing in under-resourced practices to assist in value-based care and quality improvement</header><text>Section 1848(q)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4FD508CE48BF4EFD8CCAB0594F5497EB"> <subparagraph id="HC6E520BD5AA7470DA408FB54C11A20C0" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Investing in under-resourced practices to assist in value-based care and quality improvement</header> <clause id="H5B0F1E0E231A4F07B79EB5AD0CDA9E43"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a DPPS eligible professional who furnishes covered professional services during a year that is a DPPS savings year (as defined in clause (v)) and for which the professional meets the criteria specified in clause (ii), in addition to the amount of payment that would otherwise be made for such services under this part for such year, there also shall be paid to such professional, from the amount specified in clause (iv)(I) for such DPPS savings year, a lump-sum incentive payment (in such amount as specified by the Secretary) which shall be used by such professional to improve care management, address health-related social needs, implement and further the use of certified EHR technology (as defined in subsection (o)(4)), improve performance with respect to the performance categories described in paragraph (2)(A), or implement and participate in value-based care models.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB992A09A9EB6465884732B7966354EA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Criteria</header> 
<subclause id="H8ED146C9A2694901A81B65B02C95B4B0"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Attestation</header><text>A DPPS eligible professional meets the criteria specified in this clause for a year if, with respect to such year and professional, data was submitted under this subsection and, for purposes of this subparagraph, it is demonstrated through an attestation that the professional is in a small practice described in subclause (II).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6AE67686145949A79F1620F81743E3A3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Small practices</header><text>Subject to clause (iii), a small practice described in this subclause is a practice of 15 or fewer professionals.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H6BDAAD92FD8D4FB6A781A9599ED0DE9E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Secretarial authority to give priority to certain small practices</header><text>The Secretary may, with respect to a DPPS savings year and based on the amount specified in clause (iv)(I) with respect to such year, for purposes of this subparagraph give priority to DPPS eligible professionals in certain small practices by applying clause (ii)(II) for such year as if instead of describing a practice of 15 or fewer professionals, such clause described any one or more of the following:</text> <subclause id="H6FC5F6E9D9A3472CA94450F4C93D8B1B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A practice of 15 or fewer professionals located in a rural area.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC87EB79294AB439EB69F9F7AAEAC1449"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A practice of 15 or fewer professionals located in a health professional shortage area (as designated under in section 332(a)(1)(A) of such Act).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5EE36891C9A340528099BBCAD543B798"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A practice of 15 or fewer professionals located in a medically underserved area.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H17CE6F07E13F42D7BE981D84CD445B79"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>A practice of 15 or fewer professionals with a low composite score.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA288E739F44042128AACAC9015098518"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Funding for incentive payments</header> <subclause id="H7AC4200AB859498CBEDE7606751CEDA5"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Amount available</header><text>The amount specified in this subclause, with respect to a DPPS savings year, is the amount by which the amount described in subclause (II) for such year exceeds the amount described in subclause (III) for such year.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF7FC36F0D9964255BD7646BB720D2656"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Aggregate decrease</header><text>The amount described in this subclause is the estimated decrease in the aggregate allowed charges resulting from the application of DPPS adjustment factors under subclauses (III) and (IV) of subparagraph (A)(ii) to DPPS eligible professionals whose composite performance score for a year is below the performance threshold under subparagraph (D) for such year.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H973F5710129343B5B615BFBFDF6F8BAE"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Aggregate increase</header><text>The amount described in this subclause is the estimated increase in the aggregate allowed charges resulting from the application of DPPS adjustment factors under subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) (after application of subparagraph (F)(v)) to DPPS eligible professionals whose composite performance score for a year is above the performance threshold under subparagraph (D) for such year.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC05585AAC720429DB6A03C54D8978D08"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Funding limitation</header><text>In no case may the amounts used to carry out this subparagraph with respect to a year exceed the amount specified for such year under subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2FC34C0884824A45838C3F8E15131202"><enum>(v)</enum><header>DPPS savings year</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>DPPS savings year</quote> means a year (beginning with 2028) for which the amount described in clause (iv)(II) exceeds the amount described in clause (iv)(III).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD455427BABCB4966AF5A4598E4341578"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Coordination with other incentive payments</header><text>The amount of any additional payment under this subparagraph and any other provision under this section or section 1833, including section 1833(m) shall be determined without regard to any additional payment under such other provision and this subparagraph, respectively.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

