<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFB3710FAE9344EED9202F95D849FD6D1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5860 IH: SNAP BACK Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5860</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251028">October 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the immediate release of funds appropriated for the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP) and the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC), and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0B84F8E5972940B28DD87C2D8BC535AD" style="OLC"><section id="H4649E79C6A894ACE853FE47659FEDB9C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SNAP BACK Act.</short-title></quote></text></section><section id="id63de089ada884420bbd18d28c69b5425"><enum>2.</enum><header>Appropriation</header><subsection id="id0fae2a04665042d3a41851a2c9e3c41a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>In fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter, for any period during which interim continuing appropriations or full-year appropriations for that fiscal year have not been enacted for the Department of Agriculture, there are appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture, such sums as are necessary to provide uninterrupted benefits under—</text><paragraph id="id9053cda5e42a4c958befd71705f0aa4d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C 2011 et seq.); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb3b1aac72de4f44b2473eb9229d4627"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children established by section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8EEE5C452FC24183AD42F882A0369892"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirement to release funds</header><subsection id="H28D9AF37369F4CFEBAEF78E8E8805921"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Immediate obligation of funds</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, immediately upon enactment of this Act, obligate and make available all funds appropriated by Congress for—</text><paragraph id="H6B939C9C9B8C4B668711AE7F80F90595"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the supplemental nutrition assistance program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5137C9AEEE814F87BF543BBB02F5BA37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H008F932BEE7A4DAC9E0010F07E7E6341"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on withholding</header><text>No officer or employee of the executive branch, including the Office of Management and Budget, or U.S. Department of Agriculture may withhold, delay, or otherwise impede the release or obligation of such funds for any reason not explicitly authorized by statute.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3A2D6182ADBA451F997881997E57C65D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement to enroll</header><paragraph id="H9991F14E752947E684EB6AD95C847D7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Continued enrollment</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall ensure that, all State agencies administering SNAP or WIC continue to accept, process, and approve applications for individuals and households that meet the statutory eligibility requirements for such programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DFEA501D7364A82A153EE0342EB70B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access to benefits</header><text>Individuals determined eligible under paragraph (1) shall receive benefits as soon as funds are available, and no later than five days after the Secretary obligates the funds made available under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H608764CB58904BA690C819C7678AF43E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on enrollment freeze</header><text>No Federal or State official may institute an enrollment freeze, waiting list, or other restriction on participation in SNAP or WIC due to any delay or withholding of funds.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H332C037217FD44729A3396B7548A40B2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Continuity of EBT card access and processing</header><subsection id="HD09292EBAB65462191B0403D3EB96A7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Uninterrupted operation</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall ensure the uninterrupted operation and functionality of all Electronic Benefit Transfer (EBT) systems used to distribute SNAP and WIC benefits, including during any lapse in appropriations or due to an administrative delay.</text></subsection><subsection id="H502E59A63107413CA36E0280E8E1609F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timely disbursement</header><text>State agencies administering SNAP or WIC shall, upon receipt of Federal funds, immediately load benefits onto EBT cards for eligible households without additional delay.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEDC776C878E047568BE478DCF11AA6DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on suspension of benefits</header><text>No Federal or State agency may suspend, deactivate, or otherwise restrict the use of EBT cards due to any temporary funding delay.</text></subsection></section><section id="id2fac91eb5f52413b96e8cb93ea778ae0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reimbursement of States or tribes</header><subsection id="id8367e916f705473eaf14a8e2f514e7db"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reimbursement of State or Tribe</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall reimburse any State of federally recognized American Indian Tribe that makes an emergency appropriation of State or tribal funds to cover a lapse in Federal funding for these programs up to the amount expended by the State or tribe.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

