<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H64756CB606DE4304BFE517078BDC08E3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9702 IH: Medicare-X Choice Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9702</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a public health plan.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCDA75368B34C496EAE4A85EFAA6CB811" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HA3306A20F7E94D16A9DF91EFF6FD1412"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare-X Choice Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H113C6971D13F430781E091164BF2B60C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment and administration of a public health plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Social Security Act is amended by adding at the end the following new title:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C7AB338B3EC44F584E5160E62002E16">
<title id="H3500B974773C40E9BA065E465B117997" style="OLC"><enum>XXII</enum><header>Medicare Exchange Health Plan</header>
<section id="H6EBCA905A477431DACB89E159C0975C0"><enum>2201.</enum><header>Establishment</header>
<subsection id="H37D83004CD9D482A918F837E1C1BA5A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of plan</header>
<paragraph id="H4DEB4B0C363A4D63B2F5FB257AAE5FF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a coordinated and low-cost health plan, to be known as the <quote>Medicare Exchange health plan</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>health plan</quote>) to provide access to quality health care for enrollees.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6BE87E586174B76AED04E20844D589D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeframe</header> <subparagraph id="HB4BFCC5B278547909C893D39112ABBB7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Individual market availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the health plan available in the individual market, in all rating areas, for plan year 2028 and each subsequent plan year.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H35D38FE044264DE88B8321868C754967"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small group market</header><text>The Secretary shall make the health plan available in the small group market, in all rating areas, for plan year 2028 and each subsequent plan year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9B262FBAD1A6454D872EE23D98A934C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of funds</header> <paragraph id="HB4338B3AAFE34A01ABA5DF64F3D687DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan Reserve Fund</header> <subparagraph id="HAD006C1D65B540DD820DB7FE3B81B6D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a <quote>Plan Reserve Fund</quote>, to be administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for purposes of establishing the Medicare Exchange health plan and administering such plan, consisting of amounts appropriated to such fund during the period of fiscal years 2027 through 2036.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H22ADE171116B4527AB685FA79EF8D922"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>There is appropriated $1,000,000,000, out of monies in the Treasury not otherwise obligated, to the Plan Reserve Fund for fiscal year 2027, to remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48C1CF08D4844B208CA5DD61D0A46077"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data and Technology Fund</header> <subparagraph id="H0606BC12B08740108904A1CCD4F24653"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a <quote>Data and Technology Fund</quote>, to be administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, for purposes of updating technology and performing data collection under section 2205 in order to establish appropriate premiums for all geographic regions of the United States, consisting of amounts appropriated to such fund during the period of fiscal years 2027 through 2036.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6A7B6ECEAC5447ABB828D761A90779C4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>There is appropriated $1,000,000,000, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Data and Technology Fund for fiscal year 2027, to remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBAE12FA8B3E348BF928F9041AAFF7679"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medicare-X Choice Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this title. Rules promulgated under this subsection shall be finalized not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medicare-X Choice Act of 2026</short-title>.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H15910D79854549228ADE94206F5A80EC"><enum>2202.</enum><header>Availability of plan</header>
<subsection id="H9CC915B3F5BB4C5CBED8EE7585E31371"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An individual shall be eligible to enroll in the health plan if such individual, for the entire period for which enrollment is sought—</text> <paragraph id="H719C802944244B00B5355624E4A6ED02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a qualified individual within the meaning of section 1312 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B33FC7B15124386B267FE6FA6308F61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is not eligible for benefits under the Medicare program under title XVIII.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2BA32B7FE7BD4B08A0CBAB5E3A9CDDD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exchanges</header><text>In accordance with the timeframe under section 2201(a)(2), the health plan shall be made available through the American Health Benefit Exchanges described in sections 1311 and 1321 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031</external-xref>, 18041), including the Small Business Health Options Program Exchange.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HA6F02A7F31164C1CAFF66C1DEC6783F5"><enum>2203.</enum><header>Plan requirements</header>
<subsection id="HF807A6349BB14E6980F3BE5432424654"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The health plan shall comply with all requirements, as applicable, of subtitle D of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act applicable to qualified health plans, and such health plan shall be a qualified health plan, including for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9B9DD66ED4F347529A7A651DE645455C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Levels of coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary—</text>
<paragraph id="H757B513DC8394861A4077732316643AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall make available a silver level and gold level version of the plan, in accordance with section 1301(a)(1)(C)(ii) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H765A7AD89D9442FEB4ABCBB99AF61DD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may make available no more than 2 versions of the plan for each of the 4 levels of coverage described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of section 1302(d)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2707996E46DF4E5A82A1B7AC6DF37F73"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Primary care services</header><text>The health plan shall provide coverage for primary care services, and shall not impose any cost-sharing requirements for such services.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H55EA80F963DE419D94042131872DD8EF"><enum>2204.</enum><header>Administrative contracting</header> <subsection id="HE5EDF859AE2445628529456AFE51C147"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into contracts for the purpose of performing administrative functions (including functions described in subsection (a)(4) of section 1874A) with respect to the health plan in the same manner as the Secretary may enter into contracts under subsection (a)(1) of such section. The Secretary shall have the same authority with respect to the public health insurance option as the Secretary has under such subsection (a)(1) and subsection (b) of section 1874A with respect to title XVIII.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H075530349A054CA5B1CDE53A73DFD661"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of insurance risk</header><text>Any contract under subsection (a) shall not involve the transfer of insurance risk from the Secretary to the entity entering into such contract with the Secretary, except in the case of an alternative payment model under section 2209(h).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5C26B26DAFAA434DA3A4949E208AA249"><enum>2205.</enum><header>Data collection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to all applicable privacy requirements, including the requirements under the regulations promulgated pursuant to section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note), the Secretary may collect data from State insurance commissioners and other relevant entities to establish rates for premiums and for other purposes, including to improve quality, and reduce racial, ethnic, socioeconomic, geographic, gender, sexual identity, and other health disparities, including such disparities experienced by people with disabilities and older adults, with respect to the health plan.</text></section>
<section id="HF93A7E6282EB49D488D084373D99B89A"><enum>2206.</enum><header>Premiums; risk pool</header>
<subsection id="H2CDA1CFE459D43ECACBCAF4951ED5CE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Setting premiums</header>
<paragraph id="HBF845E6098A94E748157F3F4D74DCC38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish premiums for the health plan that cover the full actuarial cost of offering such plan, including the administrative costs of offering such plan. Such premiums shall vary geographically and between the small group market and the individual market in accordance with differences in the cost of providing such coverage. If, for any plan year, the amount collected in premiums exceeds the amount required for health care benefits and administrative costs in that plan year, such excess amounts shall remain available to the Secretary to administer the health plan and finance beneficiary costs in subsequent years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H72395FBF46B5475A945145D94108D0EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial plan year</header><text>For plan year 2028, the Secretary shall set premiums for the health plan for each rating area in which the health plan is available for such plan year, taking into consideration the premium rates for plans offered in each such rating area for plan year 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H7685C438FA3B45BAAC3A6D6F43FE8B97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Risk pool</header><text>After plan year 2028, all enrollees in the health plan within a State shall be members of a single risk pool, except that the Secretary may establish separate risk pools for the individual market and small group market if the State has not exercised its authority under section 1312(c)(3) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H68B426FD1EA84846A286A003B7BD4F0D"><enum>2207.</enum><header>Reimbursement rates</header> <subsection id="HB665738B33434D6AAE719F50BA393F8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicare rates</header> <paragraph id="HBA397D408B944C08B1CC7C4AEC7E6CF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) and subsections (b) and (c) and subject to subsection (d), the Secretary shall reimburse health care providers furnishing items and services under the health plan at rates determined for equivalent items and services under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B of title XVIII.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H79E26B83EDA24616864EDFAA314E058B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to increase payments rates in rural areas</header><text>If the Secretary determines appropriate, the Secretary may increase the reimbursements rates described in paragraph (1) by up to 50 percent for items and services furnished in rural areas (as defined in section 1886(d)(2)(D)).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1029F4B3E0054A13BBBA261E023630C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prescription drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (d), payment rates for prescription drugs shall be at a rate negotiated by the Secretary. Such negotiations may be in conjunction with negotiations for selected drugs under part E of title XI.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5228140CD4FF41779841C4473317347F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional items and services</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary shall establish reimbursement rates for any items and services provided under the health plan that are not items and services provided under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B of title XVIII.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCD112513CCBB49909907615B4D322D8D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Innovative payment methods</header><text>The Secretary may utilize innovative payment methods, including value-based payment arrangements, in making payments for items and services (including prescription drugs) furnished under the health plan.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H3D3E9CCC102D48C495EC4019CA3FBAB4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comprehensive study on covering additional services</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H3515AE1497474EC5B01B7877D43CFF20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, shall conduct a comprehensive study, in consultation with stakeholders, and develop recommendations for Congress on the need for, and cost of providing coverage for, additional services under the health plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD0FB98722D444A47B53220BA8B4523D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The study shall under paragraph (1) shall include—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H895924A1640442E0A5EF588BE5E3D69E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consideration of providing coverage for long-term services and supports, home and community based services, assistive and enabling technologies, and vision, hearing, and dental services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF5322FABA1094B529C31FBE5A1F9EC31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consideration of providing coverage for other services in addition to the services described in subparagraph (A) that could most benefit the health and financial well-being of beneficiaries, including by reducing health disparities, if included for coverage under the plan;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5CDD2FD2C8DF4C459D172D087EC37D1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the costs associated with covering additional services described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), for beneficiaries through cost-sharing and premiums, and for the Federal Government; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C67DA0E224D4B849A586A9A7856ED65"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of the implications of covering such additional services for the risk pool of the health plan and for the individual and small group markets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE282CCF12676422498D8246AB1092B9E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the findings and recommendations of the study under this subsection and shall make such report publicly available on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HCE8152B6CED942739FE495B0B416D147"><enum>2208.</enum><header>Participating providers</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE76F38301B744849883D71D07E8E89E"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirement To participate in order To be enrolled under Medicare</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (d), beginning January 1, 2028, a health care provider may not be enrolled under the Medicare program under section 1866(j) unless the provider is also a participating provider under the health plan.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02C0AA9B8CAD4B9791145932E4461425"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To participate in order To participate in Medicaid</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), beginning January 1, 2028, a health care provider may not be a participating provider under a State Medicaid plan under title XIX (or a waiver of such a plan) unless the provider is also a participating provider under the health plan.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3EFF6DC07D649F29AB8F05CC25DFD8F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional providers</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process to allow health care providers not described in subsection (a) or (b) to become a participating provider under the health plan.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2BC14757FFB6421EA2A766C1234A3784"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Opt-Out</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process by which a health care provider described in subsection (a) or (b) may opt out of being a participating provider under the health plan, under exceptional circumstances where participation in the health plan threatens the provider’s ability to operate.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4B3FE3EB891D45A281E94CCA53982B45"><enum>2209.</enum><header>Delivery system reform for an enhanced health plan</header> <subsection id="H366AB3AE30D04CFDA38C5E533394626B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning with plan year 2028, the Secretary may utilize innovative payment mechanisms and policies to determine payments for items and services under the health plan. The payment mechanisms and policies under this section may include patient-centered medical home and other care management payments, accountable care organizations, accountable communities for health, value-based purchasing, bundling of services, differential payment rates, performance or utilization based payments, telehealth, remote patient monitoring, partial capitation, and direct contracting with providers.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3398219042D0470487B670B845EA9CF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for innovative payments</header><text>The Secretary shall design and implement the payment mechanisms and policies under this section in a manner that—</text> <paragraph id="HB1C8C93BC22041BFAA2F16B47E84C60E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seeks to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H924D87A5CAB946339C13C23B0AA19769"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve health outcomes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA66B9DF395594897A1794A6588900B33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce health disparities (including racial, ethnic, socioeconomic, geographic, gender, sexual identity, and other disparities, including such disparities experienced by people with disabilities and older adults);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H510A4B40D03645FC997059510787B7E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve coordination to provide more efficient and affordable quality care;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A643DFEF56343CB976FCA8C7A1EC026"><enum>(D)</enum><text>address geographic variation in the provision of health services; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H177DEA0625DD40CC856D73ECC6A28CA5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>prevent or manage chronic illness;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H051C8BAD72994742A0E7E5966BC6C8A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promotes care that is integrated, patient-centered, quality, and efficient;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEA9F55C9775545609905E90A6095B093">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>implements patient feedback mechanisms, including culturally- and disability-competent mechanisms; and</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4D161D9775AE4951BA08C5937D569260"><enum>(4)</enum><text>uses person-reported experiences to improve service delivery.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H14D01E182C9B401F96DF25AC4D8F04DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Encouraging the use of high-Value services</header><text>To the extent allowed by the benefit standards applied to all health benefits plans participating in the Exchanges (as described in section 2202(b)), the health plan may modify cost-sharing and payment rates to encourage the use of services that promote health and value.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE5BF53FDA6B84DFEA80DD909F3B841B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Promotion of delivery system reform</header><text>The Secretary shall monitor and evaluate the progress of payment and delivery system reforms under this section and shall seek to implement such reforms subject to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7B4AC1AC6B824EACAEB65F672B0676C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To the extent that the Secretary finds a payment and delivery system reform successful in improving quality and reducing costs, the Secretary shall implement such reform on as large a geographic scale as practical and economical.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF6F85B9F873540B0BCBF8D37730C1E0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may delay the implementation of such a reform in geographic areas in which such implementation would place the public health insurance option at a competitive disadvantage.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51840BBCB4074B59A054648ABE1C302B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary may prioritize implementation of such a reform in high-cost geographic areas or otherwise in order to reduce total program costs or to promote high-value care.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2968A4B89B8B4187A61925FAAC218513"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary may prioritize implementation of such a reform to reduce racial, ethnic, socioeconomic, geographic, gender, sexual identity, or other health disparities, including such disparities experienced by people with disabilities or older adults.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H27C67AD73F1C495EAD21A2979A6DB42E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Non-Uniformity permitted</header><text>Nothing in this section shall prevent the Secretary from varying payments based on different payment structure models (such as accountable care organizations and medical homes) under the health plan for different geographic areas.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HEBA5EE01E53845D5BDFF2BDB6689CA22"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Integration with social services</header>
<paragraph id="H0C0C000F6AF849A4B5B28E2CE7F72F79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish processes and, when appropriate, collaborate with other agencies to integrate medical care under the health plan with food, housing, transportation, and income assistance if the Secretary determines that such integration is expected to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D1CDD6E79B743D5ABC3D6167D09594E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce spending without reducing the quality of patient care;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H70F27541D96541A29C4E2A9D6D960E76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve the quality of patient care without increasing spending; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H186350701C34433082B552E1AC44B891"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduce racial, ethnic, socioeconomic, geographic, gender, sexual identity, or other health disparities, including any such disparities experienced by people with disabilities or older adults.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38916EA28CE64DC6BA789355A5B95380"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of a grant program</header>
<subparagraph id="HA822BD904F944FC2A2C700DD5E458B46"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may establish a grant program to permit broader experimentation with accountable communities for health model.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H665A7A58D9604B61BD8E3374A40FFBFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text>The Secretary may award a grant under this section to—</text>
<clause id="H92DD8E124B6C41C7AD0C193D6EFFF264"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an institution of higher learning (as defined in section 3452(f) of title 38, United States Code);</text></clause> <clause id="H4D6279B6160B469D9A33DFF8A5FBE690"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a local educational agency (as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965);</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF65FA4B0A89043269B8E2051929891B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a health care agency;</text></clause> <clause id="HE503F83E519F4556B7B250F0FEAA6DDC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a nonprofit entity that the Secretary determines has a demonstrated history of community engagement; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H64E49E580503412B9030DF1596F3CB9D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any other entity, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H904B6CE37DE74DF7876A8E5A884028AE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this section may use the grant to—</text>
<clause id="H76B877FD08D04FF29DF71E624550E4AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support community needs assessment;</text></clause> <clause id="H174E09F73E8644989B313FF4E5B3867E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish social service partnerships; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H4A5B38CEA9254D448AB1C11AAB25A480"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>establish interactive data systems across health and social service providers.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H605FE2897351425F8A57613D718BD0B3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H99A5A91880BC491F823ADD30AD059F5E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>If the Secretary establishes a grant program under this section, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations on—</text> <subparagraph id="H1F562C300D784E439F2765F6BC7E04BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the evaluation of applications for grants under the program; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7430878F734D429797B24EF62D0B4869"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administration of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCA03AB6B9AE24D9C8339822E2D265ACD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Telehealth</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure the integration of telehealth tools, including technology-enabled collaborative learning and capacity building models, that increase patient access to medical care (including specialty care), particularly in remote or underserved areas, if the Secretary determines that such integration is expected to—</text>
<paragraph id="HD386B6C36CEB4C0EB53D463E9858590E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduce spending without reducing the quality of patient care; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EFC9653E26A47F1970AF2F70E6508E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve the quality of patient care without increasing spending.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H42D677257F6D4C23900E24A8AC00F813"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Alternative payment model</header>
<paragraph id="HBAEB358A3D4A442AB670FA8ED5EDC54D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall evaluate the possibility of providing incentives, and, if appropriate, apply incentives, for enrollees in the health plan who receive services from providers who are participating in an alternative payment model (as defined in section 1833(z)(3)(C)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CB6B6F15A674D43839F62319D52C216"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to use apms in use under traditional Medicare</header><text>Nothing in this section shall preclude the Secretary from using alternative payment models (as so defined) under this title that are in use under title XVIII.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HCEBCED5EA5BA40C29DD75DDF22C20C09"><enum>2210.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">No effect on Medicare benefits or Medicare Trust Funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66E0FD2B07B44D1CB5A32ECC0C410999"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affect the benefits available under title XVIII; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CE41297FCDA4A48BDEC9B23BC28A4E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impact the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under section 1817 or the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund under section 1841 (including the Medicare Prescription Drug Account within such Trust Fund).</text></paragraph></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H8C49DBD9181A420297D631D84AC24BB8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exclusion of providers that place additional restrictions on Medicare exchange health plan patients from Federal health care programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1128(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H06F0CE6430054DE8A8A697A8677C5FDF" act-name="">
<paragraph id="H957C3731FFFD42EABACFB4FBDF886404"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Placement of restrictions on Medicare Exchange health plan patients</header><text>Any individual or entity that places restrictions on the individuals the individual or provider will accept for treatment and fails to either—</text> <subparagraph id="H6BC977DCBB844F41A58D1016F51142CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exempt enrollees in the Medicare Exchange health plan established under title XXII from such restrictions; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H088F092A2D4E4D3C8895251987664E90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apply such restrictions to enrollees in the Medicare Exchange health plan in the same manner and to the same extent the restrictions are applied to all other individuals seeking care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HE6ED1F0C4D9B40B8900B7BCABD52F03B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reinsurance</header> <subsection id="H6AC69837CF3244508A8A20187AEE130E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a mechanism to pool, on a nationwide basis, the costs of the highest-cost patients enrolled in individual health insurance coverage (as defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)) offered on or off the Exchanges, to the extent such costs are not already pooled pursuant to section 1343 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18063">42 U.S.C. 18063</external-xref>), for the purpose of reducing premiums for such individual health insurance coverage.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H22B25669B55B4FE5B004F7B71A2B8CB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out paragraph (1), there is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2028, 2029, and 2030.</text></subsection></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H92C9B48E5DF54FDA89CFABA680DAC70F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expansion of tax credit</header> <subsection id="HEDCBF69483ED4BA2BA8943A3A4366F6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>but does not exceed 400 percent</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0E1EBEC48134428886E819FD08C0D1F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable percentages</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B(b)(3)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE191121B6FEE4D3F9E6A3C22A3750A3C"> <subparagraph id="H37A627F3AAF1452B8FB92F600F228BC0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>The applicable percentage for any taxable year shall be the percentage such that the applicable percentage for any taxpayer whose household income is within an income tier specified in the following table shall increase, on a sliding scale in a linear manner, from the initial premium percentage to the final premium percentage specified in such table for such income tier:</text>
<table blank-lines-before="1" table-type="" table-template-name="Generic: 1 text, 2 num" align-to-level="section" frame="topbot" colsep="1" rowsep="0" line-rules="hor-ver" rule-weights="4.4.4.0.0.0">
<tgroup cols="3" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" min-data-value="180" colwidth="209pts"/><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column2" min-data-value="10" colwidth="90pts"/><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column3" min-data-value="10" rowsep="0" colwidth="89pts"/><thead>
<row><entry morerows="0" namest="column1" colname="column1">In the case of household income<linebreak/> (expressed as a percent of poverty line)<linebreak/> within the following income tier:</entry><entry morerows="0" namest="column2" colname="column2">The initial premium percentage is—</entry><entry morerows="0" namest="column3" colname="column3">The final premium percentage is—</entry></row></thead>
<tbody>
<row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">Up to 150 percent</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">0</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column3">0</entry></row>
<row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">150 percent up to 200 percent</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">0</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column3">2.0</entry></row>
<row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">200 percent up to 250 percent</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">2.0</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column3">4.0</entry></row>
<row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">250 percent up to 300 percent</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">4.0</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column3">6.0</entry></row>
<row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">300 percent up to 400 percent</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">6.0</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column3">8.5</entry></row>
<row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">400 percent and up</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">8.5</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column3">8.5.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HB1744A1BE6FD486F80E4D737020A70C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on recapture</header><text>Clause (i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(f)(2)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H421CB62E1524417F9BAD92AFC3AD9219"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In the case of a taxpayer</quote> and all that follows through <quote>the amount of the increase</quote> and inserting <quote>The amount of the increase</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF7477587148A4E138CCA14BEC621D6FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of the last row of the table; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DA05865A42C4F40A55FD849F7DCA37E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end of the table the following new row:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFABFA3AE2B214FF8AC049D28B8E25FDD">
<table blank-lines-before="1" align-to-level="section" colsep="1" frame="topbot" line-rules="hor-ver" rowsep="0" rule-weights="4.4.4.0.0.0" table-template-name="Generic: 1 text, 2 num" table-type="">
<tgroup cols="2" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" colwidth="269pts" min-data-value="180"/><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column2" colwidth="56pts" min-data-value="10"/>
<tbody>
<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">400 percent and up</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">$5,000.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0853D2E34762469B9F869343427407F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fixing the family glitch</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H04F1980FAC574E65ABE2FA1633903523"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Clause (i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(c)(2)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" act-name="" id="H0FEE8BAC295148C5A2328307FB1014B3"> <clause commented="no" id="H172CD1C499EC45C8B7D62FD369DB0F92"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Coverage must be affordable</header> <subclause commented="no" id="H326005D00B304ED2A7A84DC1AE10CA48"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee shall not be treated as eligible for minimum essential coverage if such coverage consists of an eligible employer-sponsored plan (as defined in section 5000A(f)(2)) and the employee’s required contribution (within the meaning of section 5000A(e)(1)(B)) with respect to the plan exceeds 9.5 percent of the employee’s household income.</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H53F507B5A15640DF9446F706641AEB09"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Family members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is eligible to enroll in an eligible employer-sponsored plan (as defined in section 5000A(f)(2)) by reason of a relationship the individual bears to the employee shall not be treated as eligible for minimum essential coverage by reason of such eligibility to enroll if the employee’s required contribution (within the meaning of section 5000A(e)(1)(B), determined by substituting <quote>family</quote> for <quote>self-only</quote>) with respect to the plan exceeds 9.5 percent of the employee’s household income.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H6D39C79DE474461BAF9CCBB459A77EC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC482983F34864E2E95410AF722907FA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Clause (ii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(c)(2)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>Except as provided in clause (iii), an employee</quote> and inserting <quote>An individual</quote>.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H597BE4498A5C4E409227E6325BA20C4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Clause (iii) of section 36B(c)(2)(C) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>the last sentence of clause (i)</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (i)(II)</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC3F34348C017429296DEFEAA8C1D091E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Clause (iv) of section 36B(c)(2)(C) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>the 9.5 percent under clause (i)(II)</quote> and inserting <quote>the 9.5 percent under clauses (i)(I) and (i)(II)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CDE098D8E56425B8E49707652958107"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H7E57827C3930440FAE4B6A40C1BCD45F"><enum>6.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authority to negotiate fair prices for Medicare prescription drugs</header> <subsection id="H9399136F823C43919E4183CD0F4AE7D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1860D–11 of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (i).</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF6CC19E233A4E13B9B8EDC9480FAE2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H58337BD72478403BB6B27ECC9F505562"><enum>7.</enum><header>Strengthening antitrust enforcement in health care markets</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of studying health care markets, including anticompetitive practices within those markets, and taking appropriate antitrust enforcement action for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031, to remain available until expended—</text>
<paragraph id="H610D02C68873450B90514FE399E46B09"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$50,000,000 to the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1384F1CF76E4D378B9DA2BA20D1F110"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$100,000,000 to the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H0EB7E16A72F74FD390EAFD11A5CD3937"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission shall submit to Congress a report—</text> <paragraph id="H40EAD1E85C33436290474F67A52C0E4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, detailing the activities on which the Antitrust Division or the Commission spent funds authorized under section 7; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H262CF009180140E3806E6E5E9FCD8745"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than September 30, 2032, that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H796D3430CA9642C5A392E89672C6A0F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings of any study conducted by the Antitrust Division or the Commission on or after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD2BE21258CBF4510A8BA698CF07D3DD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the activities on which the Antitrust Division or the Commission spent funds authorized under section 7; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EB25352873A4F89AC2CA76005743A2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of any enforcement action taken on or after the date of enactment of this Act by the Antitrust Division or the Commission on improving consumer access to affordable health care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

