<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H74E2CD77859C4630ADC451302AE2D1ED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8662 IH: To provide assisted living assistance through Medicaid and low-income housing tax credit.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide assisted living assistance through Medicaid and low-income housing tax credit.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1C69928B6248457695E898CD628CF5AA" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB9001E37647D40D7A5F8A8548C9B7118"><enum>1.</enum><header>Coverage of services in an assisted living residence under Medicaid</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBF4C856BEF0464D920E5FE6EC7D236D"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of medical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71E4E08DB16D41F0845B4FCFFF0D461B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (31), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48BC641010C04A7C9AF9F3647EE29534"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (32) as paragraph (33); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD092EE5F34874AAEB4FBCDA1A061F498"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (31), the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H557F613B3D0B4DFF8171B87EB6BE954F"> 
<paragraph id="HF941F701A0F543FF93409B9387723F8E"><enum>(32)</enum><text>services provided in an assisted living residence consistent with State law permitting such services, including to individuals who would require the level of care provided in a hospital or nursing facility, the cost of which could be reimbursed under the State plan (or a waiver of such plan), and who meet the State's income and resources requirements adopted under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i)(V) and for whom the estimated annual average per capita total Medicaid cost for all services for individuals receiving services in an assisted living residence would be no greater than the estimated annual average per capita total Medicaid cost for all services that would have been incurred had those individuals received services in a hospital or nursing facility; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB98EB2B96A934CE180882FCF42B5C80C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mandatory benefit</header><text>Section 1902(a)(10)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>and (30)</quote> and inserting <quote>(30), and (32)</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB28F754513F84F66974AB4F03C57F220"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<paragraph id="HF518160110C0468FB764043E077CDA74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on January 1, 2027.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABED0D0766E74AA5A022FD2617A6F04E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay permitted if state legislation required</header><text>In the case of a State plan approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this section, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title XIX solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet such additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that ends after the 1-year period beginning with the date of the enactment of this section. For purposes of the preceding sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H12D41638FACA471D86A202E6BBFE3BB0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Selection criteria for qualified allocation plan under the low-income housing tax credit</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6F1B72672E54900B6D2B382614D9418"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (C) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42(m)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (ix), by striking the period at the end of clause (x) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4AAB88C73C94787AA814F40C68EFD39"> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82120E5BE2E741F6A845951BC19204B2"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>projects which reduce the medical assistance costs of long-term services and supports for the elderly by providing such services and supports in a non-institutional setting.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56A0E5764FB54769AEF15613B5DBB2D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to allocations made after January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

