<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B79A4EF14AF4CBF81BC3281719BE25A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8375 IH: Medicare Advantage Improvement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8375</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for certain reforms under the Medicare Advantage program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H49B0AADBFAA94F60B46C2E135E783AD4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H02BD050AFC6048ED8814BBBE8B8B816C" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Advantage Improvement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H17C7C5A2722C442891E887752C1E54D6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving access to timely care for enrollees of Medicare Advantage plans</header> <subsection id="H1D4A1757B7254C59BF2C8DAA3BA96AE4"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Reducing timeframes for Medicare Advantage organizations To respond to certain authorization requests</header> <paragraph id="H8187340F15B54C2CA3877EE6CC84B370"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Standard organization determinations</header> <text>Section 1852(g)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H38103DC13382442BBEECA24F74093079">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (A), in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>subparagraph (C) and</quote> after <quote>Subject to</quote>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H91D7181C356340A7916FAFAACA7216E9">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>Such a determination</quote> and inserting <quote>A determination described in subparagraph (A) or (C)</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC7A3F2E166AF45EDA7942BBBBE31954E">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HF9E509FA8A6140C38EBB9540F3CE4EFE" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HEE7A4900927D4737B81723AE8D7E2D91"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Required timeframes for responses to certain authorization requests</header> <clause id="H941485E603184A769434667D13BBEEC9"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Subject to <internal-xref idref="HE303B18895B94D6CA3A64891018CED6A" legis-path="(C)(ii)">clause (ii)</internal-xref> and paragraph (3)(B)(iii), the procedure established pursuant to subparagraph (A) by a Medicare Advantage organization offering an MA plan shall provide that in the case of a request made on or after January 1, 2028, for a specified authorization (as defined in <internal-xref idref="H058FF0329B444F08980E67A8ABFE30C8" legis-path="(C)(iii)" >clause (iii)</internal-xref>) with respect to an individual enrolled under such plan, the Medicare Advantage organization must notify the individual (and the provider of services or supplier involved, as appropriate) of the determination regarding such request as expeditiously as the health condition of the individual requires, but, subject to <internal-xref idref="HCA1880A40A4444B0B264F3B77B67750D" legis-path="(C)(iv)">clause (iv)</internal-xref>, not later than 72 hours after receipt of the request.</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HE303B18895B94D6CA3A64891018CED6A">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <header>Extensions</header>
 <text>Subject to <internal-xref idref="HCA1880A40A4444B0B264F3B77B67750D" legis-path="(C)(iv)">clause (iv)</internal-xref>, a Medicare Advantage organization offering an MA plan may extend the deadline applied under <internal-xref idref="H941485E603184A769434667D13BBEEC9" legis-path="(C)(i)" >clause (i)</internal-xref> or the deadline applied under paragraph (3)(B)(iii)(II), as applicable, with respect to a determination regarding a specified request for an individual enrolled under the MA plan, by up to 7 calendar days if—</text>
                  <subclause id="H765A1D66D44E499B8B7A4C05E7B95408">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the individual requests the extension;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H91CFDA3086EA4D4BBB7D9D113E62F00B"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>the extension is needed for purposes of obtaining additional relevant medical evidence from a provider of services or supplier that does not have a contract with the MA organization to furnish items and services to individuals enrolled under the MA plan; or</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H84E795F6AC9547E88076EFC7CA46D8BA" commented="no">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>the extension is in the individual’s interest and is justified by reason of extraordinary, exigent, or other nonroutine circumstances that are not within the reasonable control of the MA organization (as determined by the Secretary).</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H058FF0329B444F08980E67A8ABFE30C8">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <header>Specified authorization defined</header>
 <text>For purposes of this part, the term <term>specified authorization</term>—</text>
                  <subclause id="H8DE27700B6434E0F995431387026DDC9">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>means, with respect to an individual enrolled under an MA plan offered by a Medicare Advantage organization, an authorization of coverage or payment for an item or service through—</text>
                    <item id="HB1BF7BD1633B40778F4E55BFE6A243C3">
                      <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text>a prior authorization or preservice determination of coverage or payment; or</text>
                    </item>
                    <item id="HA7A5FFF81C494558BFBA7672CB5E9C7B">
                      <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text>a concurrent determination made while the individual is receiving the relevant item or service; and</text>
                    </item>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="HD94559BF90194F79B67AFA8850980519">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>includes an authorization for a transfer of the individual between hospitals or between a hospital and post-acute care facility.</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HCA1880A40A4444B0B264F3B77B67750D">
                  <enum>(iv)</enum>
                  <header>Secretarial authority</header>
 <text>With respect to requests for a specified authorization made on or after January 1, 2030, in carrying out <internal-xref idref="H941485E603184A769434667D13BBEEC9" legis-path="(C)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref> and (ii) and paragraph (3)(B)(iii)(II), the Secretary may specify through notice and comment rulemaking a deadline other than the deadline specified in the relevant clause or paragraph.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H64F0586AE4664CD6BD50337B51B34741">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Expedited organization determinations</header>
 <text>Section 1852(g)(3)(B)(iii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(g)(3)(B)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HC3606C1EAE914EAA8BA494BD5694E7E5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">Timely response</header-in-text>.—In cases described</quote> and inserting:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6D5BD0E679A1417B8E1E7962E8E3046A"
              display-inline="yes-display-inline">
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC" >Timely reponse</header-in-text>.—</text>
              <subclause id="H007C67EC01D7470C9408290D89462920">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subclause (II), in cases described</text>
              </subclause>
              <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5C32DAB5027F4AA59ACEE689A965DD2B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block id="H5EE1B817B21643D19F2AA84E5D7DA4D8" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HA79B17C7E3204376889A20994CCBAB2E"> <enum>(II)</enum> <header>Reducing expedited timeframes for responses to certain authorization requests</header> <text>Subject to paragraph (1)(C)(ii), in cases described in clauses (i) and (ii) that are related to an expedited determination for a specified authorization (as defined in paragraph (1)(C)(iii)) for which a request is submitted on or after January 1, 2028, the Medicare Advantage organization shall notify the enrollee (and the physician involved, as appropriate) of the determination under time limitations established by the Secretary. Subject to paragraph (1)(C)(iv), such notification shall be made not later than 24 hours after the receipt of the request for the determination (or receipt of the information necessary to make the determination).</text>
              </subclause>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFBCE11730077433181F916E21DCE7BE3">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Improved transparency of certain prior authorization information on the MA plan
            level</header>
 <text>Beginning with plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, in carrying out the provisions of section 422.122(c) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H81BD5FA848364DFABF289AC0477C7741">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>require Medicare Advantage organizations to report prior authorization data described in such section on the plan level and on the Medicare Advantage organization parent level in addition to the contract level;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HCD2572928E9E48BBBA154E67ECCDFB32">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>require Medicare Advantage organizations to report prior authorization data described in such section in a manner that allows comparison of such data based on provider and service category; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA4BA6F94F02C444886C56B5635C803B2">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>in addition to making such data publicly available, as described in such section, make such data available in a downloadable format that is accessible for research purposes and oversight and enforcement activities of the Secretary.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2ACDAC3F32B34B4C9A7DD3B63F4740F8">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Real-Time authorization decisions for certain identified services</header>
 <text>Section 1852(g)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(g)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by <internal-xref idref="H1D4A1757B7254C59BF2C8DAA3BA96AE4" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, is further amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="HE30AF8C586544AA9B9896CB3616EC5F9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (A), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>subparagraph (C) and</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (C) and (D) and</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBD60B03248B94289B37B16EF0283B500">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>A determination described in subparagraph (A) or (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>A determination described in subparagraph (A), (C), or (D)</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H606ED0639AFA489C936293909A99A612">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (C)(i), by striking <quote>Subject to clause (ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to clause (ii), subparagraph (D),</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H49D0FD0B4DBA43B4B255DAF8A14F4744">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H7C89420C8399400F9FA6A5B442F030B9" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H775A33B12DA94E5AAC5FAF60262AF662"> <enum>(D)</enum> <header>Real-time authorization decisions for identified services</header> <clause id="H264676486B49447698B49A4943D93DBA"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The procedure established pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall require that the Medicare Advantage organization has in place a mechanism and process through which, beginning January 1, 2028, the organization provides a real-time determination, in accordance with this subparagraph, in response to any request for a specified authorization (as defined in subparagraph (C)(iii)) that is—</text>
                <subclause id="H10746CDA9E334989A541DE181FA7496E">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>made with respect to an item or service identified on the most recent list published pursuant to clause (iii); and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H26811C1B3B5B44A394D42D27042F97F9">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>submitted through certified EHR technology (as defined in section 1848(o)(4)).</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H1B23E165BAD6459F9D52070E97854EDC">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Requirements for real-time mechanism and process</header>
 <text>The mechanism and process required under clause (i) shall—</text> <subclause id="H8E03BE34ADA74CB5B7A6D311DE5D5822"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>include real-time tools capable of providing immediate automated approvals;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H00128FFB7047407593E179464FB2582B">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>provide for the integration of such tools in a manner that is interoperable with certified EHR technology (as so defined) used by providers of services and suppliers; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HDB9A0E2BBF3A46DCAC1FA1FA48959FB3">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>enable immediate notification to the provider of services or supplier, as applicable, of determinations, including, in the case of a denial, notification of any additional documentation needed.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H5F5BA3C100744B9EAD8AAD6CB447B28F">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Annual publication of list of identified services requiring real-time
                  authorization support</header>
 <text>For purposes of this subparagraph, for each plan year beginning on or after January 1, 2028, the Secretary shall annually establish through notice and comment rulemaking a list identifying the following items and services:</text>
                <subclause id="HB317C1B2A71C4097B29968C2B0CB0567">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Items and services for which, with respect to the previous plan year, at least 90 percent of requests for a specified authorization were approved across all Medicare Advantage organizations.</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H264237A4086147CBACE4ED3B41E38850">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>Items and services that are clinically low-risk and routine, as defined by the Secretary through notice and comment rulemaking.</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HD6256F12719A4EF281454043A8DD8CA7">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>Items and services that the Secretary identifies, according to standards specified by the Secretary through notice and comment rulemaking, as representative of significant service volume and administrative burden for acquiring such a specified authorization.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HA83CC09DFEF84232A18AF47E69DA4BDC">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <header>Improving transparency</header>
                <subclause id="HAA22F61933494AB19DDC654EF3F677A8">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <header>Quarterly MAO reports to CMS</header>
 <text>Beginning January 1, 2028, and quarterly thereafter, each Medicare Advantage organization offering an MA plan shall submit to the Secretary (in a form and manner specified by the Secretary) information (presented by provider and service type) regarding real-time determinations made by the organization during the previous quarter pursuant to this subparagraph, including information on—</text>
                  <item id="HEB3F97687ED54ED0B890621ADFA57571">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of real-time determinations made during the quarter, and the percentage of all determinations made during the quarter with respect to an item or service identified on the most recent list published pursuant to clause (iii) that were real-time determinations;</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="HA8E5A34A8C7B4659867AC64F35A5296F">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text>the number and percentage of real-time determinations made during such quarter that were approved;</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="HF65469F97A88430EB5EDEBB0B57AED08">
                    <enum>(cc)</enum>
 <text>the number and percentage of such determinations that were denied;</text> </item> <item id="H05131C19A3A24900B372955CFE505A54"> <enum>(dd)</enum> <text>the number and percentage of such denied determinations that were appealed;</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="HA737E9067BA242D1A3B1766183B0880C">
                    <enum>(ee)</enum>
 <text>the number and percentage of such appealed determinations that were overturned; and</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="H60E601613E144BCA90C5F0584E2815DE">
                    <enum>(ff)</enum>
 <text>the number and percentage of provider complaints regarding the mechanism and process implemented by the Medicare Advantage organization pursuant to this subparagraph. </text>
                  </item>
                  <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subclause">The information submitted
                    pursuant to the previous sentence shall include such information and be provided
                    in such a manner to enable comparison and analysis of such information on the
                    Medicare Advantage organization level, Medicare Advantage parent organization
                    level, and MA plan level.</continuation-text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HA8FB20D718E042A99496EC0D6E7F6F57">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <header>Public availability of information</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall make information collected under subclause (I) publicly available on the internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H485F522870DA40BD815B0FCAD0AF2446"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibiting certain authorization processes for certain clinically necessary changes and extensions</header><text>Section 1852(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H958041E1F6D04A63BEBA513FF939DD0A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3816C221FBCD480A9B159EAFDDE06E32"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Prohibition on requiring certain authorizations</header><text>Beginning January 1, 2028, in the case that a Medicare Advantage organization offering an MA plan provides approval through a specified authorization (as defined in subsection (g)(1)(C)(iii)) for an item or service to be furnished to an individual enrolled in the plan by a provider of services or supplier, if during the course of furnishing such approved item or service the provider of services or supplier determines that a modification, extension, or adjustment to such item or service is clinically necessary, the Medicare Advantage organization may not require a specified authorization (as defined in subsection (g)(1)(C)(iii)) to be requested with respect to such item or service as so modified, extended, or adjusted. Application of the previous sentence shall not limit the authority of the Medicare Advantage organization to require documentation or post-service notification of any such modification, extension, or adjustment.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A09C16D80594A75BF54F571967C6928"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Improvements to the reconsiderations process</header><text>Section 1852(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE31F9613F79E44048CBC8BC11F672FBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7760427EE4024F47A50FD3D91634134C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>(or, with respect to determinations made on or after January 1, 2028, not later than 14 days)</quote> after <quote>60 days</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83640A9A7CAC4547A2543A402D6A4FD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H54FC3285AD4B4A63B4A6379B7FCAF98E" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HA5D24A8207AC4152818BB73CA87544B3">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Reconsiderations affirming denials of coverage</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a reconsideration affirms (in whole or in part) a denial of coverage (including an adverse organization determination under section 422.590 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation) made on or after January 1, 2028, with respect to an individual enrolled in an MA plan offered by a Medicare Advantage organization, the Medicare Advantage organization shall submit to the independent, outside entity with a contract under paragraph (4) the case file and written explanation of the decision as expeditiously as the individual’s health condition requires, but not later than 14 days after the date the Medicare Advantage organization received the request for the reconsideration.</text>
              </subparagraph>
                            <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8A9355CD6574D64827A6697770FC712"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF4287FE9B5E4F08A7BDC37891392D70"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">coverage denials</header-in-text>.—The Secretary shall contract with</quote> and inserting:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5B67517F680E4B7C999F50B368ACBB1C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">coverage denials</header-in-text>.—</text> <subparagraph id="HF220F3F30FD544F58077ED962FB82C1C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall contract with</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6694A42031B4E2588EEE003F16CEC00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block id="HE351C10EB3594FC895C3F9A918E40F0B" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HB33A18BF0363445DBB85CC20BF97F222"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In reviewing and resolving pursuant to subparagraph (A) a reconsideration of a determination of a Medicare Advantage organization made on or after January 1, 2028, with respect to an individual enrolled in an MA plan offered by the organization, the independent, outside entity shall comply with each of the following requirements:</text> 
<clause id="H2673DEA02C854D18B7D0A1AB9D546247"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice and opportunity to provide supporting documentation</header><text>The entity shall—</text> <subclause id="H8164BCE4E7FB4441A8BBDF9F04A24EF1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not later than 3 days after the date of receipt of the relevant case file from the Medicare Advantage organization, submit to the individual, the representative of the individual (if applicable), and the provider of services or supplier furnishing (or ordering) the item or service that is the subject of the determination, a notification regarding the opportunity to submit documentation, including medical records, regarding medical necessity; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8BB9885F862041BBA940995A38DAE01E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide a period of 7 days from the date of receipt of such notification for submission of any such documentation.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB7B869F75C75487BB431586727C17E17"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Decision timeframe</header><text>After reviewing and considering all supporting documentation received before the end of the 7-day period described in clause (i)(II), the entity shall issue its decision with respect to such reconsideration as expeditiously as the individual’s health condition requires, but by not later than the applicable number of days specified in subparagraph (C) after the last day of the 7-day period described in clause (i)(II).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61C05E49BC3D4D4880F23D557B96302E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable number of days</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B)(ii), the applicable number of days specified in this subparagraph is—</text> <clause id="HEE5FC18D118140848A14780EC0FF1E41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>14 days, in the case of a request (other than with respect to an expedited reconsideration under paragraph (3)) for coverage of an item or service that is not a drug for which payment may be made under part B;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB8AEEEDDE3EB479FA053B55318B0F0F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>7 days, in the case of a request (other than with respect to an expedited reconsideration under paragraph (3)) for coverage of a drug for which payment may be made under part B;</text></clause> <clause id="H88CF3FE4A5494399B0F0B3F0440D7C32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>30 days, in the case of a request (other than with respect to an expedited reconsideration under paragraph (3)) for payment of an item or service; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H31649A98014D4AF0B8BEA21B8C73E42D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>24 hours, in the case of a request with respect to an expedited reconsideration under paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H81BAA25F46CF4D439F0209BE675501AF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ensuring appropriate oversight of Medicare Advantage plans</header> <subsection id="H3A51B551168E49A8943161B438823C99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>MAO compliance scoring and accountability program</header><text>Section 1853 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB2F36B643DDA4C7EBCCE7953C49F53B6" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HBC01FE27FE60436A8A4936EC81ECA0E5"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Compliance scoring and enforcement</header> 
<paragraph id="HB73E352E0F174D3BAE8D021ECB3D7B10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment reductions for MAOs in noncompliance with certain MA program requirements</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF2E1806002994B498CD0CA5F0E8FB6CD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a Medicare Advantage organization with a contract under this part that the Secretary determines, in accordance with this subsection, to be within a compliance tier specified in <internal-xref idref="H925BF6FFBF564820AA52FCEC07DADA39" legis-path="(p)(1)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref> for a performance period with respect to a plan year beginning on or after January 1, 2028, the Secretary shall reduce the total of the monthly payments made for the plan year under section 1853(a)(1) to the Medicare Advantage organization with respect to each Medicare Advantage plan offered by such organization by the applicable percent specified under <internal-xref idref="H925BF6FFBF564820AA52FCEC07DADA39" legis-path="(p)(1)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref> with respect to the compliance tier.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H925BF6FFBF564820AA52FCEC07DADA39"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable percent specified</header><text>For purposes of <internal-xref idref="HF2E1806002994B498CD0CA5F0E8FB6CD" legis-path="(p)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, the applicable percent specified under this subparagraph is as follows:</text> 
<clause id="HDECE968CD25B4E20B76048BE10692096"><enum>(i)</enum><text>With respect to the compliance tier described in <internal-xref idref="HF29832037A2A4420824AEA04176A5F20" legis-path="(p)(5)(B)">paragraph (5)(B)</internal-xref>, 1.0 percent.</text></clause> <clause id="HF57210CDA0E249D2B5717884B92571D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>With respect to the compliance tier described in <internal-xref idref="HA8B3A8CA58A7418AACF8724E5DDD0A57" legis-path="(p)(5)(C)">paragraph (5)(C)</internal-xref>, 1.5 percent.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6274C59213DD41C095600A519AF45449"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>With respect to the compliance tier described in <internal-xref idref="H758B8EB3145E4F52B1B0A1CDC108BF75" legis-path="(p)(5)(D)">paragraph (5)(D)</internal-xref>, 2.0 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4362DCCB129A4F16875C7E02C6FEFB2C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Performance period</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish a performance period (or periods) for each plan year beginning on or after January 1, 2028. Such performance period (or periods) shall begin and end prior to the beginning of the plan year and be as close as possible to such plan year. In this subsection, such performance period (or periods) for a plan year shall be referred to as the performance period with respect to the plan year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3593269204E342E58AF82F5DF43A15CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of compliance scoring and accountability program</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish a Medicare Advantage organization compliance scoring and accountability program (referred to under this subsection as the <quote>MAO Compliance Program</quote>) under which, for each Medicare Advantage organization with a contract under this part and each performance period with respect to a plan year beginning on or after January 1, 2028, the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D6E52F6899F46A9A2D820710A305759"><enum>(A)</enum><text>using the method established under <internal-xref idref="H3450C2060F6940819DF413F8EDAF1C0F" legis-path="(p)(3)(A)">paragraph (3)(A)</internal-xref>, shall assess the extent to which the Medicare Advantage organization is in compliance with requirements under this part applicable to each compliance category specified under <internal-xref idref="H957C8CEE2FE84F57893CD15EF30B02A6" legis-path="(p)(3)(B)">paragraph (3)(B)</internal-xref>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7D42ECD8BF9A4C32B9F1FB131555EE0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>based on such assessments for each such compliance category, shall assign a total compliance score to the Medicare Advantage organization, in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H4000A33B5C154DEFAABE49834876BAA6" legis-path="(p)(4)">paragraph (4)</internal-xref>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF32D1823A784F81A03237884D057B98"><enum>(C)</enum><text>based on such total compliance score, shall assign the Medicare Advantage organization to a compliance tier described in <internal-xref idref="H3DBDB369807D4591889462BD3B478C61" legis-path="(p)(5)">paragraph (5)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4F9CDD745A640D1B8C73F57F0F8F3A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assessment method</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3450C2060F6940819DF413F8EDAF1C0F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the MAO Compliance Program, the Secretary shall establish through notice and comment rulemaking a method to assess, at the plan level, the extent to which each Medicare Advantage organization offering a Medicare Advantage plan is in compliance with requirements under this part applicable to each compliance category specified in <internal-xref idref="H957C8CEE2FE84F57893CD15EF30B02A6" legis-path="(p)(3)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>. Such method shall include the use of audit mechanisms, reporting requirements, performance measures established or identified by the Secretary (such as applicable measures under the MA Program Compliance and Coverage Protection Domain described in section 1853(o)(8)), and such other methods as specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H957C8CEE2FE84F57893CD15EF30B02A6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance categories</header> <clause id="H7C3AF8039F704D4A9D96CD01830B79E7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to <internal-xref idref="HEBDC2FCF81AE401CAE0EAEA40CCD7B29" legis-path="(p)(3)(B)(ii)">clause (ii)</internal-xref>, under the MAO Compliance Program, each of the following shall be a compliance category:</text> 
<subclause id="HA29B186C4F2643F1A1F99A7A0743FEA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Compliance with timely and real-time specified authorization decision-making requirements, including compliance with section 1852(d)(7) and paragraphs (1)(C), (1)(D), and (3)(B)(iii)(II) of section 1852(g).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H543DB71AB4D640A394FF42DFA71500BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Compliance with coverage criteria standards, including the requirements under section 1852(g)(7) and section 1852(a)(2)(D).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H21D05F23FDAE4DF08554E6AD1666EE1A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Compliance with prompt payment requirements, including compliance with section 1857(f).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1A35AAD3AF9348E88BED835FA262C224"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Compliance with restrictions regarding improper retroactive denials and downgrades, including compliance with section 1852(g)(6) and section 1857(e)(6).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1D018961AC1F45CFB782FB3C8070595B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Compliance with marketing, enrollment, and beneficiary communication requirements, including subpart V of part 422 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor to such regulations.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD355F52730C940A9885AB49D9FF5E166"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Compliance with other requirements under this part, including section 1852(g)(1)(E) and such other requirements as specified by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HEBDC2FCF81AE401CAE0EAEA40CCD7B29"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary may, through notice and comment rulemaking, revise the compliance categories described in <internal-xref idref="H7C3AF8039F704D4A9D96CD01830B79E7" legis-path="(p)(3)(B)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref>, including by specifying additional categories, removing categories, and otherwise updating the requirements that are included in any of such compliance categories.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4000A33B5C154DEFAABE49834876BAA6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Scoring methodology</header><text>Under the MAO Compliance Program, the Secretary shall, through notice and comment rulemaking, establish a methodology to assign a total compliance score (using a scoring scale of 0 to 100) to each Medicare Advantage organization for the performance period with respect to a plan year. Such total compliance score shall be based on the assessment under <internal-xref idref="HB4F9CDD745A640D1B8C73F57F0F8F3A6" legis-path="(p)(3)">paragraph (3)</internal-xref> of plan-level compliance with respect to each compliance category described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph, with each such category receiving equal weight (and, in the case of a Medicare Advantage organization offering more than one plan during the performance period, with each such assessment weighted by the number of individuals enrolled under such plan during such period).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DBDB369807D4591889462BD3B478C61"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Compliance tiers</header><text>For each plan year beginning on or after January 1, 2028, the Secretary shall, based on the total compliance score assigned pursuant to paragraph (4) to a Medicare Advantage organization for the performance period with respect to such year, assign such Medicare Advantage organization to one of the following compliance tiers, as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H9D42D33877E1415FB5A5C038E83BFCA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Compliance tier one, consisting of Medicare Advantage organizations receiving a total score for the performance period of at least 90.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF29832037A2A4420824AEA04176A5F20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Compliance tier two, consisting of Medicare Advantage organizations receiving a total score for the performance period of at least 75 but not more than 89.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8B3A8CA58A7418AACF8724E5DDD0A57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Compliance tier three, consisting of Medicare Advantage organizations receiving a total score for the performance period of at least 60 but not more than 74.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H758B8EB3145E4F52B1B0A1CDC108BF75"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Compliance tier four, consisting of Medicare Advantage organizations receiving a total score for the performance period of less than 60.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CC769981F28406191EEDCD0B726D137"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process under which a Medicare Advantage organization may seek a review of the total compliance score assigned to the organization pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H4000A33B5C154DEFAABE49834876BAA6" legis-path="(p)(4)">paragraph (4)</internal-xref> for a performance period.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84A48BB3227C40C398BE55113847FD84"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Public disclosures</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4C065E46EE1F48C2A2116161A446A61F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each plan year beginning on or after January 1, 2028, the Secretary shall make available on a public website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and in an easily understandable format, information regarding the assessments under the MAO Compliance Program of compliance during the performance period with respect to the plan year by Medicare Advantage organizations, on the plan level, with requirements applicable to each compliance category specified in paragraph (3)(B). Such information shall include the total compliance score received by each Medicare Advantage organization pursuant to paragraph (4) for the performance period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H271D39D6F94744E8973F4BE6CE21B6B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Opportunity to review and submit corrections</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for an opportunity for a Medicare Advantage organization to review and submit corrections for the information to be made available under <internal-xref idref="H4C065E46EE1F48C2A2116161A446A61F" legis-path="(p)(7)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> with respect to such organization prior to such information being made public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA3B5A9ABA02D4695B22494B5804570C0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Expanding the MA star ratings program To include an MA program compliance and
          coverage protection domain</header>
        <paragraph id="HC5E59642153D4D9AA9977A7BAA3240D7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Data collection</header>
 <text>Section 1852(e)(3) of the Social Security Act (1395w–22(e)(3)) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H468AFE7DE3C84642B2B3F0CE0029CC1E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in subparagraph (A)(i), in the first sentence by inserting <quote>, including, for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, with respect to measures under the MA Program Compliance and Coverage Protection Domain described in section 1853(o)(8)</quote> after <quote>other indices of quality</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFF73904D9FD24F78BBBAD4F693BDC5A5">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by inserting <quote>, and other than the types of data authorized under subparagraph (C) of section 1853(o)(8) for purposes of the MA Program Compliance and Coverage Protection Domain described in such section</quote> after <quote>as of November 1, 2003</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC8F2DE88FC914C0FA6EC5304B44579FD">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Addition of MA program compliance and coverage protection domain to MA star
            ratings system</header>
 <text>Section 1853(o) of the Social Security Act (1395w–23(o)) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
          <quoted-block id="HD0736A39EF8D4D86A95EA531264BE274" style="OLC">
            <paragraph id="H21707704429541799589D8D3E35D00DB">
              <enum>(8)</enum>
              <header>MA program compliance and coverage protection domain</header>
              <subparagraph id="H5FB2F1733EE2430CA493B764048070B6">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, in addition to any other domain under the 5-star rating system under paragraph (4)(A) used for determining star ratings of Medicare Advantage plans, the Secretary shall include under such system an MA Program Compliance and Coverage Protection Domain.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H61D23AF891AB44AEB03244BCFAC4167F">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Measures</header>
 <text>Such domain shall include measures to assess compliance of each Medicare Advantage plan with each of the compliance categories specified in section 1853(p)(3)(B).</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4BD3E9B845F5447D991D1E0552DC3411">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Data</header>
 <text>For purposes of determining star ratings with respect to measures under the MA Program Compliance and Coverage Protection Domain, in addition to sources of data otherwise collected under section 1852(e)(3), the Secretary may use data collected pursuant to audits, complaint tracking systems, appeals data, determinations made by independent review entities, and such other sources as specified by the Secretary.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H244EC5B5421241D8A86A318C302AF7F4">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <header>Application of weighting</header>
 <text>In applying section 422.166(e) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation, with respect to the MA Program Compliance and Coverage Protection Domain, the Secretary shall assign a weight to measures included under such domain that is greater than the weight assigned to measures included under any other domain.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H4E5794F3694743F89EF13942FB8407F1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Guardrails on retrospective clawbacks</header> 
<subsection id="HC589D811E41843D8BC4E83C91E733914"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application of prompt payment requirements to all claims for which authorization was provided</header><text>Section 1857(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H58C5FEF9247D4A9C926B55C610990854"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEC82A942713B4DE28550010EF49EFB1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the header, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">for items and services furnished by out-of-network providers of services and suppliers</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">requirement</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9FC7EC60A6894F4FBBFCD69F6FCEFE7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A contract</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (2), a contract</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1544C4C4D21D4A5D8ABF17B2308B799B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>in compliance with paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>in compliance with paragraphs (1) and (2)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42DCB5BAA14C457D980D309EDC360EA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76B84B358F5B46559198B36D04E287BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HACFDCAC0E68E4F888292D2EDE475071A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H796BECD4401D48DC82E505C23215EAB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement for items and services for which authorization was provided</header> <subparagraph id="H14421D1A445C438ABDB852A4FB02110B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For contract years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, a contract under this part shall require a Medicare Advantage organization to provide prompt payment (consistent with the provisions of sections 1816(c)(2) and 1842(c)(2)) of qualifying claims submitted for authorized items and services (as defined in subparagraph (B)) furnished to enrollees under the plan, except that in applying the provisions of such sections—</text> 
<clause id="H7FC5BEFB1AE24FABB5215D7998ACC94E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>references to <quote>not less than 95 percent of all claims submitted</quote> shall be treated as references to <quote>100 percent of all claims submitted</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFD37BA3E909D4633A4818759A0E61D54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>every qualifying claim (as described in <internal-xref idref="HAF64D2B1EECA4BC1A3AF96BAE2B29C08" legis-path="(2)(C)">subparagraph (C)</internal-xref>) submitted for an authorized item or service shall be deemed to be a clean claim referred to in such sections.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35BAA49BAA194958B5CCB2156281B0BE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized item or service defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>authorized item or service</term> means an item or service—</text> <clause id="H7C9C5B0B21CE451D8161153F516CE6E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is furnished by a provider of service or supplier to an individual enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan offered by a Medicare Advantage organization; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFECC2D9E86AE46AE87484454D6B14516"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which approval was provided by the Medicare Advantage organization through a specified authorization (as defined in section 1852(g)(1)(C)(iii)).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF64D2B1EECA4BC1A3AF96BAE2B29C08"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualifying claim described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, a claim for an authorized item or service is a qualifying claim if it includes information sufficient to establish that approval for such item or service was provided as described in <internal-xref idref="HFECC2D9E86AE46AE87484454D6B14516" legis-path="(2)(B)(ii)">subparagraph (B)(ii)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CBD7F6C8333472D97B3F6B8D6F16F59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of specified authorizations</header><text>Section 1857(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395e-27">42 U.S.C. 1395e–27(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H677CB17FFED54A82B2F250BDD0367DDF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H87179359EEB147018DEF05668CF6EB3C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Effect of specified authorizations</header><text>Beginning with plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, a contract under this section with an MA organization shall require that, in the case that the MA organization approves the furnishing to an individual enrolled under an MA plan offered by such MA organization of an item or service through a specified authorization (as defined in section 1852(g)(1)(C)(iii)) made during the receipt by the individual of such item or service—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF173EC972E9540B28E4B030CD0572C36">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the MA organization may not, after such approval, deny coverage of such item or service on the basis of lack of medical necessity and may not reopen such a decision for any reason except for good cause (as described in sections 405.986 and 422.616 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation)) or if there is reliable evidence of fraud or similar fault (as such terms are defined in section 405.902 of such title (or any successor regulation), as determined in accordance with section 422.616 of such title (or any successor regulation)); and</text>
                        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H408CEC0BB5C54F4C97DAA33061CE8735" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the MA organization may not, after such approval, change the code assigned with respect to the claim for such item or service such that the amount of payment for such claim would be reduced, except for good cause (as described in <internal-xref idref="HF173EC972E9540B28E4B030CD0572C36" legis-path="(6)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>) or if there is reliable evidence of fraud or similar fault (as so described).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5FF830C095D24F9BAEB0FF36BB5E1A57"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Limitation on use of third-Party post-Claim review entities</header> <text>Section 1852(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-2">42 U.S.C. 1395w–2(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
        <quoted-block id="H56F5E6A7A16A40BE9A795358A512AA67" style="OLC">
          <paragraph id="HCD7DA7A9A51B44F3A9B32E8FD68490D8">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Limitations on use of third-party reviews</header>
            <subparagraph id="H4209E960CE6A49498D2A261C966C7AFC">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
 <text>For contract years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, procedures established by a Medicare Advantage organization for making determinations under paragraph (1), reconsiderations under paragraph (2), or expedited determinations or reconsiderations under paragraph (3), and procedures established for providing for any post-payment review process shall—</text>
              <clause id="H15CD7523D74C45D6B84CE0829758571B">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>prohibit any third-party entity from conducting a medical necessity review for coverage, payment, or post-payment review for such Medicare Advantage organization unless—</text>
                <subclause id="H8FAEEEB595B04AA8BD0B41E45D7C8084">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>such review is not with respect to an authorized item or service (as defined in section 1857(f)(2)(B)); and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HAA82ED2C449B4E3F8F7FAC894547BDED">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>such entity is in compliance with the requirements described in subparagraph (B);</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H8E90217310FB4DDCAD06EE02CD2D3FDB">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>prohibit the use of any third-party review that is conducted using a routine, automated process for denials in any such review, claim denials, or pattern-based practices of changing a code assigned with respect to a claim for an item or service furnished to individuals enrolled under an MA plan offered by the Medicare Advantage organization to a code that would result in a reduction in the amount of payment for such claim after the item or service has been furnished to the individual; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H8DCDE3D4FC834523BA54CFDE04C5E423">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>prohibit any compensation arrangement with any third-party entity that provides for payment or other compensation to such entity based on the number, percentage, or amount of specified authorization requests (as defined in section 1852(g)(1)(C)(iii)) that the entity approves, denies, or otherwise recommends for approval or denial.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H60138DF2E5604CF0BF78B4881EB4A69B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Requirements</header>
 <text>For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H4209E960CE6A49498D2A261C966C7AFC" legis-path="(6)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, the requirements specified in this subparagraph, with respect to a third-party entity and a review described in such subparagraph, are each of the following:</text>
              <clause id="H50FCE5E2E75E4BA2906C3EB26D9B3F5D">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>The entity conducts such review in accordance with audit protocols and appeal rights, as applicable, that are specified by the Secretary.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HD16039DC7EAD4F26ADF3344E54F514A7">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>The entity complies with audit and public transparency reporting requirements specified by the Secretary.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H15E3A665DBB34682992B4A4734F8E089"><enum>5.</enum><header>Coverage and medical necessity criteria used by Medicare Advantage organizations</header> 
<subsection id="HDBAE13BB5EF24088A18CC5B01492C06D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Codification under the Medicare Advantage program of two-Midnight benchmark and
          presumption rules</header>
 <text>Section 1852(g)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(g)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
        <quoted-block id="HA686533A221647848E6F7EFC025C3A1F" style="OLC">
          <subparagraph id="HBBE2AFAB871F49D7A97C3DF9E77213AD">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <header>Application of two-midnight rules</header>
 <text>The procedures under subparagraph (A) shall provide that, for making determinations described in such subparagraph with respect to hospital and critical access hospital admissions—</text>
            <clause id="H4CE87DA27BBA4DB2A9F3ACBD6CBA4A4A">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>in determining whether an individual is an inpatient of a hospital or critical access hospital, the Medicare Advantage organization shall continue to apply the provisions of section 412.3(d) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply with respect to payment under part A; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H9574AC5A4F6A4498BF59452F1D1A420E">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>beginning on January 1, 2028, in conducting medical review activities, with respect to such admissions, the Medicare Advantage organization shall apply the 2-midnight presumption finalized in the rule published by the Secretary in the Federal Register on August 19, 2013 (78 Fed. Reg. 50952), or any successor regulation, in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply with respect to payment under part A.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H910995FB1AB64D36B5ECED0BE8B4E0FC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Requiring consistent medical necessity criteria between Medicare Advantage and
          original fee-for-Service</header>
        <paragraph id="H5902FC0B2852470F9DC0D2221AD3DEFD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text>Section 1852(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(g)</external-xref>), as amended by section 4(c), is further amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H80A50C05A33C4FF297390BBB6866A783">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>A reconsideration relating</quote> and inserting <quote>In accordance with paragraph (7)(C), a reconsideration relating</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5C9B772A91C1454BA3CD8918AA3EB007">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HC50237D344284C8EB8A8A0679EE39859" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC826144C6F384392839AC8D765CFE23D"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Medical necessity determined based on FFS reasonable and necessary criteria</header> <subparagraph id="H9863E586E68D46C3A0441699646EF991"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>For purposes of a determination or reconsideration under this subsection made on or after January 1, 2028, or a review made on or after such date by an independent, outside entity under paragraph (4), with respect to coverage for an item or service furnished to an individual enrolled in an MA plan offered by a Medicare Advantage organization, the Medicare Advantage organization or independent, outside entity, respectively, shall not apply criteria for determining the medical necessity of such item or service that is more restrictive than the standards and criteria applied pursuant to section 1862(a)(1) for determining under parts A and B whether the item or service is reasonable and necessary.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H167718A6EFDF464A95601C2992CF5C11">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Certain coverage criteria</header>
 <text>For purposes of a determination or reconsideration under this subsection made on or after January 1, 2028, or a review made on or after such date by an independent, outside entity under paragraph (4), with respect to coverage of inpatient hospital services furnished by a rehabilitation facility (as referred to in section 1866(j)(1)(A)) or long-term care hospital to an individual enrolled in an MA plan offered by a Medicare Advantage organization, the Medicare Advantage organization or independent, outside entity, respectively, shall not apply coverage criteria that is more restrictive than the standards and criteria applied under parts A and B, including under—</text>
                  <clause id="H1DF0C48EC09349A9B1B2D7C01B23FA62">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>subsections (a)(3), (a)(4), and (a)(5) of section 412.622 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor to such regulation), with respect to such a rehabilitation facility; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H3388B61CFE834A558CCABBF542E266CA">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>paragraphs (1), (3), and (4) of section 1861(ccc) and clauses (iii) and (iv) of section 1886(m)(6)(A), with respect to a long-term care hospital.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H70958425A879452888D8A87C99036F36">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Personnel</header>
 <text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a determination, reconsideration, or review regarding the medical necessity of an item or service shall be made only by a physician or other health care professional with appropriate expertise, including education, with respect to such item or service and the related standards and criteria applied pursuant to section 1862(a)(1). For purposes of subparagraph (B), a determination, reconsideration, or review regarding coverage of inpatient hospital services furnished by a facility or hospital described in such subparagraph shall be made only by a physician or other health care professional with appropriate expertise, including education, with respect to such services and the related standards and criteria applied pursuant to such subparagraph.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9344EAF7FCDC4C5282CC76E76E457996">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Enforcement</header>
 <text>Section 1857(g)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HB96F7DC72F524BB48617BB4625F7D7C1">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>by redesignating subparagraph (K) as subparagraph (L);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C4784C2566D44F1A2319E51F1E9D534"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (J);</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H0AB793FE13AA4985B29E84486EBB0BB2">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after subparagraph (J) the following subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H0E976666B4B640DE8B6AF6B1D7606AFB" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE86EA73CAC284D11ADE85F9C118E0907"> <enum>(K)</enum> <text>fails to comply with section 1852(g)(7); or</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8618EA37F1864B84A13DDE9416799EFA">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (L), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (J)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (K)</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA0DF60DBBBDE416FB99AC37AA5F9F955">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>in the matter following such subparagraph (L), by striking <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (K)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (L)</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA87A5007F9CD456B9D31AC87D649D303"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requiring transparency in coverage criteria</header><text>Section 1852(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H3D814663602D4112AB6218DA7605D64E" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H2DB2F6DD96BA4BF5B9C33141CB79B48B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Transparency in coverage criteria</header> <clause id="HD73257DA560C40D28F023739999A6E39"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, in order to meet the requirement under paragraph (1)(A), in the case of an item or service for which there is no national coverage determination, applicable local coverage determination, or applicable guidance for coverage provided by the Secretary, a Medicare Advantage organization offering an MA plan shall—</text> 
<subclause id="HCF22B43BAE854AFA91BB33F7D59DE331"><enum>(I)</enum><text>make a coverage determination with respect to such item or service in accordance with publicly available evidence-based coverage criteria that is published on a public website of the Medicare Advantage organization; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA654DF9E60144DF5A523390E3C8B9C72"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary information, with respect to every medical necessity determination made in the absence of such national coverage determination, applicable local coverage determination, or applicable guidance for coverage, specifying the coverage criteria applied under the MA plan.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H52F73CCD928F40DAA8CA90D09A5E18F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>The Secretary shall use the information submitted under clause (i)(II) to prioritize coverage determinations.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H4197B0CA12D14F149EE63824F8C17517"><enum>6.</enum><header>Eliminating inefficiencies in administrative processing by Medicare Advantage organizations</header> <subsection id="H4D4E60449E694321BFC15F527CEF7605"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Applying fee-for-Service prompt payment requirements to MA in-Network services as well as out-of-Network services</header> <text>Section 1857(f)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(f)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by section 4(a), is further amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H30D8AD5FEC4A4D2A8F75D091C1C2ACAE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">in-network and</header-in-text></quote> before <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">out-of-network</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7CAFFC609A584FE0AC0A5232022AF02B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>if the services or supplies</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>regardless of whether the services or supplies are furnished under a contract between the organization and the provider of services or supplier. A claim that is determined to be a clean claim pursuant to the previous sentence or paragraph (2) may not subsequently be determined to not be a clean claim except under such circumstances and in accordance with such criteria as specified by the Secretary pursuant to notice and comment rulemaking.</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC159FB9AD7B442F198A952D34B998F11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Automated review and payment for certain claims</header><text>Section 1857(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(f)</external-xref>), as amended by section 4(a), is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD0FA5D6DE7924049976E766FFAD6BB58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4B1F75D6A48431FBE1323C4CD8052E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H2F00DEF3572E4484A11297EAAC052A60" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB96BC47A33B1472581008B49A22C1920"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Automated review and payment for certain claims</header> <subparagraph id="HDB9CBD5AD1A243C0AF7F68AC0FE40B78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, a Medicare Advantage organization shall have in place automated payment processes, in accordance with standards specified by the Secretary, for claims described in subparagraph (B) with respect to which the provisions of paragraph (1) or (2) apply. Such processes shall provide that such claims shall be automatically processed and paid and shall not be subject to manual claim review, except in cases for which there is reasonable evidence of fraud.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H222101772BF84DC9B0F595EEAD892A0B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified claims</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a claim described in this subparagraph is a claim that—</text> <clause id="H9DD1ADF94493448C9ED94975D50BFAA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is for an authorized item or service (as defined in paragraph (2)(B)); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD79C8299EF1D4684963FD8F32CF8226B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is for an item or service identified on the most recent list published pursuant to section 1852(g)(1)(D)(iii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H65DBF14441804A23BFE21F751A68DE00" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Modification to network adequacy standards for certain post-acute care providers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1852(d)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC8ED180A9E0A4684AF1F1D79A4C75B7F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5A7E5611A254785BF556E9335191BB4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD36FFD186674852B43BDFBC577860EE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H46DDB076BF9E4282AAA8AE8294DAD5B3" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HA21E096634614CE09787EE45511EC194" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, the organization provides adequate access to long-term care hospitals and inpatient rehabilitation facilities, as determined in accordance with network adequacy standards specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

