<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HA000D72B54EE4D2F8D18E0E202144DC9">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9770 IH: Continuing Appropriations Act, 2027</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9770</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260718">July 18, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2027, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body style="traditional" id="H2FC59C0EC39549FBAD2FE754040DCC79">
<section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1B6A7B6F0311461CB2E60321B5E538F1"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following sums are hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, for the several departments, agencies, corporations, and other organizational units of Government for fiscal year 2027, and for other purposes, namely:</text></section> <section id="H1B6A7B6F0311461CB2E60321B5E538F9"><enum>101.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate for operations as provided in the applicable appropriations Acts for fiscal year 2026 and under the authority and conditions provided in such Acts, for continuing projects or activities (including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees) that are not otherwise specifically provided for in this Act, that were conducted in fiscal year 2026, and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available in the following appropriations Acts:</text>
<paragraph id="H78C0043477854AE3946E2DAC775789E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2026 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/37">Public Law 119–37</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD56F1FDA2134FA88BC028C35599B4E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2026 (division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/74">Public Law 119–74</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD2B2B5852F37457CAC82FBB7E4F0235E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2026 (division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/75">Public Law 119–75</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60602545E3774225A69800D802E3164E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2026 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/74">Public Law 119–74</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H15B1B2B56A8745FAA359F9487FEA81E7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2026 (division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/75">Public Law 119–75</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40E57F2B2A034D639DF84A1DD41674FA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2026 (division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/86">Public Law 119–86</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F3179B7CB31464FBAC32F4D8AB6F08E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2026 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/74">Public Law 119–74</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC425A447CCA944D9B199B4E503C88DAF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2026 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/75">Public Law 119–75</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F159FA538CC4BBD8243C90872F0327E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2026 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/37">Public Law 119–37</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E44C58E22514C7CB65AD49873C0E72F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2026 (division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/37">Public Law 119–37</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F302E066EE647CA82A4EFC1C3694B64"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The National Security, Department of State, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2026 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/75">Public Law 119–75</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A1798186E5C4EA39C27D112B53AC6FC"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2026 (division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/75">Public Law 119–75</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HD9937C5253E2498C9FD5FD7096B060BE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>102.</enum>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H01955303208942D08FA5C418BE3861A4"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No appropriation or funds made available or authority granted pursuant to section 101 for the Department of Defense shall be used for:</text> <paragraph id="H4ED526E0389A4260AFE2ECF77A9477B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the new production of items not funded for production in fiscal year 2026 or prior years;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCA67191B3507440DB56F82585E9BFF8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the increase in production rates above those sustained with fiscal year 2026 funds; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3AC0BE7D6A6480E812044A6DE2D79B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the initiation, resumption, or continuation of any project, activity, operation, or organization (defined as any project, subproject, activity, budget activity, program element, and subprogram within a program element, and for any investment items defined as a P–1 line item in a budget activity within an appropriation account and an R–1 line item that includes a program element and subprogram element within an appropriation account) for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were not available during fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4944944D79C64AE89ABC2D5C82BF74B8"><enum>(b)</enum><text>No appropriation or funds made available or authority granted pursuant to section 101 for the Department of Defense shall be used to initiate multi-year procurements utilizing advance procurement funding for economic order quantity procurement unless specifically appropriated later.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1228F95147F64A79ADF66C56AD9D792C"><enum>103.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations made by section 101 shall be available to the extent and in the manner that would be provided by the pertinent appropriations Act.</text></section>
<section id="H505AC019C8B3413FBCC001D185E1661A"><enum>104.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in section 102, no appropriation or funds made available or authority granted pursuant to section 101 shall be used to initiate or resume any project or activity for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were not available during fiscal year 2026.</text></section> <section id="HD4244E943B814CECBE3395FE3732BEA5"><enum>105.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations made and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall cover all obligations or expenditures incurred for any project or activity during the period for which funds or authority for such project or activity are available under this Act.</text></section>
<section id="HCDF339DD7D4945FC89E79DAD3F03C8C5"><enum>106.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise provided for in this Act or in the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2027, appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs:</text> <paragraph id="HAB475E0CE85649A981C0D88BB5CF4067"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7F5DA5AE34814A31818973FDF8F70223"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2027 without any provision for such project or activity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD04D78897354443AA719C747623F048"><enum>(3)</enum><text>December 4, 2026.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HEB924344DB4B4418A226A7A663B4D47F"><enum>107.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expenditures made pursuant to this Act shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever a bill in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is contained is enacted into law.</text></section> <section id="HDC198705377B44F5BEF47D8B2224FCD8"><enum>108.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations made and funds made available by or authority granted pursuant to this Act may be used without regard to the time limitations for submission and approval of apportionments set forth in section 1513 of title 31, United States Code, but nothing in this Act may be construed to waive any other provision of law governing the apportionment of funds.</text></section>
<section id="H35B180DFC1B24931883F41796AB42622"><enum>109.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, except section 106, for those programs that would otherwise have high initial rates of operation or complete distribution of appropriations at the beginning of fiscal year 2027 because of distributions of funding to States, foreign countries, grantees, or others, such high initial rates of operation or complete distribution shall not be made, and no grants shall be awarded for such programs funded by this Act that would impinge on final funding prerogatives.</text></section> <section id="H950571D44C9A4699BF64786E1F01C67F"><enum>110.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall be implemented so that only the most limited funding action of that permitted in the Act shall be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities.</text></section>
<section id="HC6D1682D49C540DCB366409A6E10C290"><enum>111.</enum>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA9FF07C3ED824A9E8BD232E5E3085606"><enum>(a)</enum><text>For entitlements and other mandatory payments whose budget authority was provided in appropriations Acts for fiscal year 2026, and for activities under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, activities shall be continued at the rate to maintain program levels under current law, under the authority and conditions provided in the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2026, to be continued through the date specified in section 106(3).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5B9F1FA66B314DAE8A7586F16AB996A5"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 106, obligations for mandatory payments due on or about the first day of any month that begins after October 2026 but not later than 30 days after the date specified in section 106(3) may continue to be made, and funds shall be available for such payments.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HC2D6CBA03B614DCB9EF7B165828E37DC"><enum>112.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available under section 101 for civilian personnel compensation and benefits in each department and agency may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs within such department or agency, consistent with the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2026, except that such authority provided under this section shall not be used until after the department or agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses.</text></section> <section id="HDA47909F980E48259D6D69F89FEE19B8"><enum>113.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated by this Act may be obligated and expended notwithstanding section 10 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/672">Public Law 91–672</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2412">22 U.S.C. 2412</external-xref>), section 15 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2680">22 U.S.C. 2680</external-xref>), section 313 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6212">22 U.S.C. 6212</external-xref>), and section 504(a)(1) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3094">50 U.S.C. 3094(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text></section>
<section id="H15ADC44D1803423FB6EEFAC245DDCA67"><enum>114.</enum>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1B8249D7310D450EB7AA781E18C6B348"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD372866ED9EB4014975F2AFABF6785AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For each amount incorporated by reference in this Act that was previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(a)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, each provision of law designating each such amount as an emergency requirement pursuant to such section shall not apply.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C348604BC9049B590ABF21582E6D501" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each amount incorporated by reference in this Act that was designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, or pursuant to section 4001(a)(1) of S. Con. Res. 14 (117th Congress), the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2022, and to legislation establishing fiscal year 2026 budget enforcement in the House of Representatives, is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 4001(a)(1) of S. Con. Res. 14 (117th Congress), the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2022, and to legislation establishing fiscal year 2027 budget enforcement in the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF8964581372D4A25A1DEC39559A8061E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Each amount incorporated by reference in this Act that was previously designated by the Congress as being for disaster relief pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(D) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 is designated by the Congress as being for disaster relief pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H73F6A8A2A9EA48B9B751543A68251C05"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Each amount incorporated by reference in this Act that was previously designated in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/159">Public Law 117–159</external-xref>, division J of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>, or in section 443(b) of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref> by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget shall continue to be treated as an amount specified in section 103(b) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/5">Public Law 118–5</external-xref>.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H6883DBA8A6344FD79FA82ADB806452EE"><enum>115.</enum>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB49F88C619F84A6898AF7A7F7BA21292"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Rescissions or cancellations of discretionary budget authority that continue pursuant to section 101 in Treasury Appropriations Fund Symbols (TAFS)—</text> <paragraph id="HC6CE88EE082C4D25848772150BC25945"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to which other appropriations are not provided by this Act, but for which there is a current applicable TAFS that does receive an appropriation in this Act; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59E06FACAB244D0D891AFE5DE3267108"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which are no-year TAFS and receive other appropriations in this Act, </text></paragraph><continuation-text>may be continued instead by reducing the rate for operations otherwise provided by section 101 for such current applicable TAFS, as long as doing so does not impinge on the final funding prerogatives of the Congress.</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection id="H96D9F47CC0554FEEA9D4BE4F591E79BA"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Rescissions or cancellations described in subsection (a) shall continue in an amount equal to the lesser of—</text>
<paragraph id="HC7F9B481632E400383114EDBF4F0758C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount specified for rescission or cancellation in the applicable appropriations Act referenced in section 101 of this Act; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF39E0517188C41CFB9021F860CC6B724"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of balances available, as of October 1, 2026, from the funds specified for rescission or cancellation in the applicable appropriations Act referenced in section 101 of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE2C040D1C7794899BA040D453C234E25"><enum>(c)</enum><text>No later than November 20, 2026, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall provide to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a comprehensive list of the rescissions or cancellations that will continue pursuant to section 101: <italic>Provided,</italic> That the information in such comprehensive list shall be periodically updated to reflect any subsequent changes in the amount of balances available, as of October 1, 2026, from the funds specified for rescission or cancellation in the applicable appropriations Act referenced in section 101, and such updates shall be transmitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate upon request.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4C94D28D523C467EA3335C78A5AE7999"><enum>116.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Domestic Food Programs—Food and Nutrition Service—Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC)</quote> may be apportioned at the rate for operations necessary to maintain participation.</text></section>
<section id="HD981A2F5A4FE4FEA9E92D6E7D9915DA6"><enum>117.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 260 of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1636i">7 U.S.C. 1636i</external-xref>) and section 942 of the Livestock Mandatory Reporting Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1635">7 U.S.C. 1635</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/78">Public Law 106–78</external-xref>) shall be applied by substituting the date specified in section 106(3) of this Act for <quote>September 30, 2026</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H94275159066C475986539EC8D6994BD3"><enum>118.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Small Business Administration—Business Loans Program Account</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to accommodate increased demand for commitments for general business loans authorized under paragraphs (1) through (35) of section 7(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)</external-xref>), for commitments to guarantee trust certificates authorized by section 5(g) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/634">15 U.S.C. 634(g)</external-xref>), for commitments to guarantee loans under section 503 of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/697">15 U.S.C. 697</external-xref>), and for commitments to guarantee debentures under section 303(b) of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/683">15 U.S.C. 683(b)</external-xref>).</text></section>
<section id="H0C78C3B52CC446CF97084362CA19D8B3"><enum>119.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, except section 106, the District of Columbia may expend local funds made available under the heading <quote>District of Columbia—District of Columbia Funds</quote> for such programs and activities under the Fiscal Year 2026 District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2026 (title IV of Division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/75">Public Law 119–75</external-xref>) at the rate set forth in the Fiscal Year 2027 Local Budget Act of 2026 (Bill 26–0659) as modified as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> <section id="HD233932E19FA435FAA257F433EC80E92"><enum>120.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H69C6F764E258412A8175922474665F79"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 101, section 747 of title VII of division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/75">Public Law 119–75</external-xref> shall be applied by—</text>
<paragraph id="H66510150A2AC4386B8E282913D521F5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>substituting <quote>2026</quote> for <quote>2025</quote> each place it appears;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2967E5F3FFAB4BF29E350D85A410E2F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>substituting <quote>2027</quote> for <quote>2026</quote> each place it appears;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF12A33E006C54FCAA92F5FFC675A47BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>substituting <quote>2028</quote> for <quote>2027</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4AC42BE063E44483A574EFABF033766E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>substituting <quote>section 747 of division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/75">Public Law 119–75</external-xref></quote> for <quote>section 747 of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>, as continued in effect and modified by section 1605 of title VI of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/4">Public Law 119–4</external-xref> (as continued in effect and modified by division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/37">Public Law 119–37</external-xref>)</quote> each place it appears.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H6B05E7C4E9EC4C9FAB5A880E6E7CE73B"><enum>121.</enum>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE4EDB86788CD4AE6BFD85096F530E882"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Sections 1309(a) and 1319 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4016">42 U.S.C. 4016(a)</external-xref> and 4026) shall be applied by substituting the date specified in section 106(3) of this Act for <quote>September 30, 2026</quote></text></subsection> <subsection id="H1B6A7B6F0311461CB2E60321B5E538F2"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1B6A7B6F0311461CB2E60321B5E538F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), this section shall become effective immediately upon enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE45C22CF06284072A715434C3116654C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If this Act is enacted after September 30, 2026,</text></paragraph></subsection><continuation-text continuation-text-level="section">this section shall be applied as if it were in effect on September 30, 2026.</continuation-text></section> <section id="H3D72A6C0740C46B0A369B9066BEAA1DA"><enum>122.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 to the Department of Homeland Security under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Disaster Relief Fund</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to carry out response and recovery activities under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section>
<section id="H3C7DD052620C49A5B8EACF3C8B3A18D9"><enum>123.</enum>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7E6AFA314D1E4E8E8A3068F420036628"><enum>(a)</enum><text>In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, amounts are provided for <quote>Department of Health and Human Services—Indian Health Service—Indian Health Services</quote> at a rate for operations of $75,774,000, for an additional amount for costs of staffing and operating facilities that were opened, renovated, or expanded in fiscal years 2022, 2026, and 2027, and such amounts may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to staff and operate such facilities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1B6A7B6F0311461CB2E60321B5E538F4"><enum>(b)</enum><text>In addition to amounts otherwise provided by section 101, amounts are provided for <quote>Department of Health and Human Services—Indian Health Service—Indian Health Facilities</quote> at a rate for operations of $8,296,000, for an additional amount for costs of staffing and operating facilities that were opened, renovated, or expanded in fiscal years 2022, 2026, and 2027, and such amounts may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to staff and operate such facilities.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HC27521ECA4C84A6CA78EAB430919561E"><enum>124.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period covered by this Act, section 1701 of title VII of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/43">Public Law 117–43</external-xref>, as amended, shall be applied by substituting <quote>calendar years 2021 through 2026</quote> for <quote>2021 or 2022 or 2023 or 2024</quote> each place it appears.</text></section> <section id="H5488ED670FC348938BF011E5756E2A15"><enum>125.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available by section 101 for <quote>Department of the Interior—Department-Wide Programs—Wildland Fire Management</quote> and <quote>Department of Agriculture—Forest Service—Wildland Fire Management</quote> may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary for wildfire suppression activities.</text></section>
<section id="H14D64B62290E46E4B46CCC66875C7EFB"><enum>126.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities authorized by part A of title IV (other than under section 403(c) or 418) and section 1108(b) of the Social Security Act shall continue through the date specified in section 106(3), in the manner authorized for fiscal year 2026, and out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are hereby appropriated such sums as may be necessary for such purpose.</text></section> <section id="H0A9B594F30E54AECA14BDF938CC1C9A7"><enum>127.</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, there is appropriated—</text>
<paragraph id="HE2551C79D08F46B48D237C5BD06E6090"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for payment to Alfredia Scott, widow of David A. Scott, late a Representative from the State of Georgia, $174,000; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70D931B5303D4CFD82A272EE13059B08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for payment to the heirs at law of Lindsey O. Graham, late a Senator from South Carolina, $174,000.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H0BA24AB143C7426F8FF69037328BD7FD" indent="subsection"><enum>128.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no adjustment shall be made under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) (relating to cost of living adjustments for Members of Congress) during the period covered by this Act. </text> <paragraph id="g123" indent="subsection"><enum/><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Continuing Appropriations Act, 2027</short-title></quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


