<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA92B0015E40C4FC69C9B212E9AE73D0F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9345 IH: Medicaid Equal Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9345</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to establish a resources test for eligibility under the Medicaid program for the expansion population.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H071BB7F448234209BBEBFC2851C74A54" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5C02470083B544889C2A721DD542BABC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Equal Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC97CE055C89643A09726779AF5592E75"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishing a resources test for eligibility under the Medicaid program for the expansion population</header> <subsection id="HF2D7476FA7664C319637B878E7DF2547"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902(e)(14) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(e)(14)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC677CEFF591E4218927AA5572DCA806C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>A State</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subparagraph (M), a State</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDABE6D4E563D4BEB919D3C127CA141CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H55F585C37B064A9BB99C51854BABB48E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HC8B2625B84464BA9839203FBDF09D94D"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Resources test for expansion individuals</header> 
<clause id="H8B4DD375ACA248E986CCDE88D37B34F4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, a State shall provide, as a condition of eligibility for medical assistance for an applicable individual (as defined in clause (v)), that such individual satisfy a resources test established by the State that meets the requirements of clause (ii).</text></clause> <clause id="HD6597429369044298DBE90F544D9298B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Resources test requirements</header> <subclause id="HABCE6F93F6374530A934BB95EEAA8B8E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), subject to subclause (III), a resources test established by a State meets the requirements of this clause if—</text> 
<item id="H52E944DF59E24116B18C828CDD34A7A3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the test precludes eligibility for medical assistance for any applicable individual whose resources (as determined under section 1613 for purposes of the supplemental security income program) exceed the amount specified in subclause (II) (or, in the case such individual is married, double such amount); and</text></item> <item id="H636CB5E9A1F04E21B58223E7BDE2940F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the State provides for application of such test at such times as are specified in clause (iii).</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB91A03D6D60544C5B0BF3AA87073019D"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Amount specified</header> 
<item id="HDAB8D249874446579C213DBAC9C98A83"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subclause (I)(aa), the amount specified in this subclause is—</text> <subitem id="H112CCF1C78464F9CA5FE73556B401927"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>for 2029, $10,000;</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H20EFDB6EFF7D4D888E49F165C6CE93ED"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>for each subsequent year (other than an applicable year), the amount specified in this subclause for the previous year; and</text></subitem> <subitem id="H4F667ECE65684960804988574430E273"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>for an applicable year, the amount specified in this subclause for the previous year, increased by the percentage change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers over the 4-year period ending on September 30 of such previous year.</text></subitem></item> 
<item id="HE0810CF9DF704715B41DD1642A55C655"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Applicable year defined</header><text>For purposes of item (aa), the term <quote>applicable year</quote> means 2033 and every fourth year thereafter.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H69EE423FF18446C7B54DEEE3BBA5B77C"><enum>(III)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text>A State may elect, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary—</text> 
<item id="H4C5520528429452093686C0E164941DE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to apply, in lieu of the dollar amount described in subclause (I)(aa) applicable to an applicable individual for a year, such lower amount specified by the State; or</text></item> <item id="H171750A805004C3BABE0639909F06A9A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to take into account resources specified by the State that would otherwise be excluded under section 1613 in determining the resources of an individual.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6017DDBEE8884E9F98D3E28FEB933B0E"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Process to exercise State flexibility</header><text>A State’s election under subclause (III) may not be denied by the Secretary and shall take effect at such time and for such period of time as the State specifies in such election. </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5434AC255E704BC986C9E52B7BFD698C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Application of test</header><text>A State shall provide that a resources test described in clause (i) is applied—</text> 
<subclause id="HCED8DEA590B94C67B39C0FF59395004D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an applicable individual who has filed an application for medical assistance under a State plan (or a waiver of such plan) under this title, at the time of the initial determination of such individual’s eligibility; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2E848A34F343439DB65556D372FB1E2D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an applicable individual enrolled and receiving medical assistance under a State plan (or under a waiver of such plan) under this title, at the time of each redetermination of eligibility for such individual.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HDC1483C512B743DCB6F28F31514589EB" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Treatment with respect to certain FMAP increases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall not be treated as not providing medical assistance to all individuals described in section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII), or as not expending amounts for all such individuals under the State plan (or waiver of such plan), solely because such an individual is determined ineligible for medical assistance under the State plan (or waiver) on the basis of a failure to satisfy a resources test described in clause (i).</text></clause> <clause id="H1A26513296DB4B13B4D767272A083B56"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Applicable individual defined</header> <subclause id="H7737B1043C894C4B9B0456B2C44D9175"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, subject to subclause (II), the term <quote>applicable individual</quote> has the meaning given such term in subsection (xx)(9)(A) and does not include any specified excluded individual.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF0F23D62035F4B00A436F5F5269E7DBD"><enum>(II)</enum><header>State option to expand definition of applicable individual</header><text>A State may, for purposes of this subparagraph, elect to include as applicable individuals any category of specified excluded individuals, or all such specified excluded individuals, as determined appropriate by the State.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAE2036CC096F4C6F9FC6E0713BE2853D"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Specified excluded individual defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this clause, the term <quote>specified excluded individual</quote> has the meaning given such term in subsection (xx)(9)(A)(ii).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD419449AEA694722A279C38C4863A64E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text>Section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9611C48C643F4A37AC7C19B97F5A6D72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (89), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33E24C827D75410C9FFDB2A0CAA79192"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (90), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BD9537714104958B5373D3B54384750"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (90) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33521C321A9D4195B6C847335CB70CD3"> 
<paragraph id="H4C6D8B04D4D0436C8459D7FC211AEFD9" indent="up1"><enum>(91)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that the State meets the requirement described in subsection (e)(14)(M).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4B7DEF1CE3324D2881578F4C0F729E27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply beginning January 1, 2029.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

